You are not generating enough electricity.
We need more electricity.
Faster.
Spin those wheels.
What's up, guys?
We are ready for season three.
Hold on.
Of course, I got my Coke.
Can't start a new season without that.
Cheers.
Oh, yeah.
I am so ready.
Are you excited?
Do you even know what you're excited for?
Dude, that's like 1,400 people watching.
Damn.
You guys like Minecraft, huh?
Well, so do I.
And, guys, I hope you haven't been expecting, like, something insane in terms of mods.
Okay?
It's not that crazy.
I've got a couple mods.
But I just want to play Minecraft.
I've got that Minecraft itch, you know?
I'm just going to play Minecraft with a couple mods.
And a little secret inside, too.
A mod that none of you have ever played.
In fact, I'm the first to play this mod.
It's not the gym mod.
Or the Jenny mod.
It's the Frank mod.
It's a new innovation.
No, really, though.
So, uh, in order to get this mod created, that I will be playing today, no pun intended.
I had to spoil myself a little bit.
It's not a lot, though.
I know a couple things about create, okay?
There's fucking ads?
Why are they playing ads now?
Hold on, I'm going to stop talking for a bit.
I'm not going to say anything until the ads are done.
Why are the ads playing?
Stupid ads.
I swear I didn't click it.
That's, like, the worst time to click it.
I was just about to explain.
Are the ads gone?
You still have ads?
35 seconds.
Okay, I'll wait 35 seconds.
Thank you for the gifted subs, guys.
And also the...
The singular subs.
I really appreciate it.
Okay, I think we're back.
Was it 90 seconds of ads?
Why?
Hey, at least there's not going to be ads for a while now.
Alright, check it out.
So, I had to spoil myself a little bit to get this mod created, okay?
So, I know about andesite.
I know about diorite.
That's from an earlier session of Minecraft.
I know that there's a machine that can press things, turn them into sheets.
I know that there's airplanes.
And, uh, what else do I know?
I'm trying to rack my brain right now.
Oh yeah, there's a system called Ponder.
And I think I understand roughly how it works.
I had to understand that to get this mod made.
To get it up to quality assurance, okay?
Other than that, it's pretty much blind.
I know some little things about the UI and stuff like that, right?
But, yeah, all in all, I did my damnedest to stay as blind as possible.
So, yeah.
It's gonna be create with something a little extra.
You'll get to see what it is along with me, okay?
That's the whole plan.
Worst case, it all crashes and burns.
It doesn't work and...
Ah, we'll figure it out.
I don't think that's gonna happen, though.
It's...
It's gone through some...
Some testing.
Okay!
What's new from you guys, anyway?
It's Friday today!
I chose this day because it's Friday.
It had to be a Friday, right?
Yeah.
We got the Coke, we got Minecraft, we got Friday.
This time, though, I have a cat with me.
That's amazing.
What's up, Jackie?
She's actually in here.
Looking up at me.
No, you can't be on stream.
There's no camera setup.
Maybe later.
Okay.
Let me actually switch over to some Minecraft music here.
There no sound?
There's sound.
There it is.
Guys, I'm gonna be playing on Peaceful.
No, I'm not.
We're gonna play hard.
Of course.
I'm gonna call this world...
I don't know.
The modern world.
Modern world.
Because it's gonna be modern, right?
Maybe, maybe...
Contemporary world.
I like that.
That's a good name.
Okay.
I hope this works.
It should work.
Again, don't expect anything crazy, okay?
I'm gonna play Minecraft.
That's really what it is.
I'm just gonna play some Minecraft.
I've got the itch.
But this time, there's a couple bells and whistles attached to it.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Always exciting when you make a new world, right?
Or you're gonna spawn.
Stuff like that.
Man.
It's been a while.
I need to let it load.
So I'm in a swamp.
Or a marshland, whatever it's called.
The place with the frogs.
I think I wanna go to...
Maybe I should...
Okay, hold on.
So this is where I spawn, right?
I should make a base here.
That's actually the first thing we need to do.
Dude, my game is lagging right now.
It's probably just because it's generating all these landscapes.
The landscapes I will explore.
Dude, it has been so long since I've actually legitimately just sat down and played Minecraft.
Well, it's been since season two, I guess.
That's been a while.
First steps first.
We're gonna make this.
No.
Whoops.
I already forgot, dude.
There we go.
And now we make a table.
Actually, I should make an axe for anything else.
28.
It's a new age.
Oh, I need to grab these, actually.
Dude, this time around, I'm gonna change things up.
I will focus on breeding.
Animals.
And farming.
From the get-go.
Imagine Interstellar.
You know, the beginning.
I'm not gonna spoil too much, but, you know, it takes place out in Oklahoma or some shit.
It's like very flat terrain.
They've got fields made of corn.
They've got actresses starring in porn.
I had to rhyme, okay?
No, no, no.
But, uh, it's gonna be like that.
You know?
And apparently, maybe I can even make a car.
So I will be recreating the scene from Interstellar.
Where I'm driving through the cornfields.
And after that, I'm gonna take off in the rocket and go to space.
Oh, I shouldn't have spoiled that.
Oops.
Oh, no.
Now they know what mods I'm using.
Shit.
Why am I fucking using a sapling to cut down trees?
What is wrong with me?
Hold on.
Need one of these.
Actually, I should...
Dude, I should go for stone immediately.
But you gotta make the essentials.
Also, this right here is for the new stuff.
This is for the old stuff.
This is the blueprint book.
Okay?
That's why it's blue.
Oh, give me this.
Oh, my God.
Dude.
It took forever to destroy that with the axe.
I forgot how terrible wood is.
Let's actually get some stone.
Also, I have to remember where I am.
Ew!
That is like an ultimate crime up there.
What is happening?
I don't want to have this be my spawn.
That's disgusting.
Let me get all this.
Yeah, let's actually...
Dude.
How about we make a little base inside the mountain?
This is like the first stage.
The cornfields come later.
This is just the beginning where we have to survive, right?
Because we are playing on hard and, you know, enemies are kind of dangerous.
Also, guys, I know I keep saying this, but now that I've had so much experience with Minecraft, I will tell you right now.
I will not die a single time in this entire world.
For all intents and purposes, this is a hardcore run.
And you can hold me to it.
There's no way I can lose.
I'm a professional at this point, you know?
Okay, so we got some stone here, so I really need to start doing this.
Oh, yeah!
Wait!
Look at this stuff here!
Simulated.
Welcome to Create.
Create Aeronautics.
Okay.
I'm not gonna get overwhelmed immediately.
I'm gonna get the basics up and going, and then we'll see what happens.
That's probably enough.
Why am I doing this?
Just do it like this.
So, apparently, this version of Minecraft is the latest version that supports Create.
So, we're not gonna have bronze stuff.
Or, no, wait.
Copper.
Like, the copper stuff is not included in this one.
So, we're actually taking a couple steps back, which is weird, but, you know.
This way this.
Let's make a sword as well, actually.
Oh, a shield!
Oh, wait.
That requires iron.
Oh.
We should really go get that.
Also, quickly do this.
I forgot what setup I usually have for my items.
Coal!
Quick coal, and then we have to make a shelter.
This is the plan.
Ugh.
Maybe this version of Minecraft has more crimes.
I don't know.
This is a very high level of...
Ooh.
Very unusual level of crimes.
Ooh, we got...
Dude, we have, like, every single biome that's, like, you know, fake desert down there.
We got greenery and whitery.
Or, uh, snow.
Oh, I got coal.
Let's get that.
Oh, I should make a shovel.
Gotta get the basics, right?
Look at this.
I just need a shield.
I need a shelter.
And a bow is not strictly necessary, but...
Like, it's...
Would be nice.
And when I have all that going, we can start looking at, uh...
the new stuff, right?
Although, be warned, I may already have forgotten some of the old stuff.
Thank you.
So, I know that you need andesite to get things, uh, kicked off with this, apparently.
So, I will be looking for that.
I actually don't know what andesite looks like.
Even though I saw the block just the other day when I was, uh, making sure it worked.
But I think I'll know it when I see it.
Uh, that's diorite.
That's not andesite.
They look kind of similar, though.
Okay, I think I should make my base here.
Oh!
Iron!
At this height?
Isn't that, like, really unusual?
Usually you find this in caves.
This run is blessed.
I wonder if I can actually kill the dragon with this, like, have they disabled that with these mods or something?
Probably not, right?
Wait, that's it?
Okay.
Let's not, uh, look a gift horse in the mouth.
Wait, what the hell is that?
Oh, it's the glowing thing.
I need to make torches.
Dude, I'm so back already.
I just gotta get the feeling into my fingers, you know?
Better grab all of this because we're gonna need it.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I actually, I need to do something before the sun goes down.
This is very important.
I need to find a sheep and kill it so I can make a bed.
This is, like, mega important.
Otherwise, I'm gonna have to hide inside all night.
This is, like, a rookie mistake here.
It's soon, uh, night time.
We gotta go to green areas.
Yeah!
Look at that!
Great start.
Oh, shit!
Dude, I forgot how far you can jump.
I don't have it in me anymore.
I forgot the muscle memory's failing me.
Ah, wait, this is a brown sheep.
Uh, I can't mix these two colors, right?
To make one bed.
Give me that.
That's one.
I think I need three.
Sheep, sheep, sheep.
I saw another one.
Wasn't there another sheep here?
Wait, what does it make?
Uh, how do I make a bed?
I don't even know how to make a bed!
Oh, wait, I do.
We have to probably use this.
Should be able to...
Oh, actually, let's kill these as well.
I'm gonna crit your ass.
Give me your meat.
There were so many comments on YouTube lately on the first season, and people were so distraught over the fact that I essentially didn't kill any animals for, like, the first big chunk of the game.
And I'm like, I just...
I didn't want to kill animals, you know?
Felt bad.
And also, like, who hunts a cow in real life?
Who just goes out on a field and slays it, you know?
It's kind of messed up, but I'm gonna do it now.
Because I'm gaming the game.
I require chops made of pork.
Wait, uh...
Oh, no!
Oh, I'm gonna have to stay inside.
Please give me a sheep.
Scanning.
Really?
Oh, oh, here we go, here we go.
No, they're chickens.
Ah, shit.
Um, well, I may be...
Oh, actually, hold on.
We can do something.
Wait, what?
Oh.
Huh?
I don't have the recipe for...
I forgot how to make a shield.
Shit.
Isn't it just wood and freaking...
Oh, I know what it is.
I know what it is.
We need stone.
Oh, it's too late.
We gotta go make a shelter.
I'm digging myself into the mountain.
There's no shame in retreating.
It happens.
Not a great...
Oh.
Never mind, never mind!
Hey!
We got pets over here!
Dude, let's go there.
Oh, we've got skellies already.
This is not great.
Also, I can't...
Oh, I can't sprint because I don't have food.
Okay, let's go.
Oh, man, look at this civilization.
Maybe this is my home!
Do I turn this into my temporary home before I go to Oklahoma?
Get out!
Nice.
Very good.
I'm getting advancements made as well.
I can't believe they call it that.
Like, hello?
Call it achievements.
Like, normal people.
Wait!
Oh, right.
So, these are the normal ones and these are the new.
Kind of weird they would put the new ones over here and not over here, isn't it?
Yeah, so this is the one.
Obtain some andesite alloy.
Creates most important resource.
That's all I really know.
We need andesite.
And then something happens.
And then life is good, apparently.
Dude, I should actually be stealing everything here.
This is like the ultimate start.
Wait, I've never seen homes like this.
Look at these designs.
This is like weirdly different from the normal houses they make, isn't it?
Oh, maybe not actually.
Hey, kitty cat.
I need a bed.
I gotta steal a bed.
And I gotta get some food going.
Meaning I need an oven.
I can probably just use one of these ovens.
Ah, here we go.
Thank you.
Good start.
Oh, wait a minute.
There's no pouches in this one then.
Or maybe there is.
I forgot which version that was.
That is a freaking disaster, guys.
How am I gonna live without pouches now that I've tasted the sweet stuff?
You know?
I don't think there's a furnace here.
We're gonna make one.
God, I hate not being able to sprint.
But look, this is what I mean when I say I'm not gonna die.
Because I was in dire straits just now, but then I made a logical decision that I never would have made in the past.
You know?
I just went to a village.
Hello?
Game is like easy if you think about it.
You don't have to make it hard on yourself for no reason.
Okay, now...
Whoop.
Furnace.
Smoker.
Let's make some food.
Get that going.
And...
Next step.
I think we should get full iron before we do anything else.
Just for survival reasons.
And also just logical reasons.
What are you looking at?
Oh, wait.
Are you one of these?
Hmm.
Oh, wait.
I don't have any money.
This is gonna take a while.
I have to remember this spot here.
This is a good spot.
Oh, finally.
Oh, yeah.
Now we're cooking.
Hmm.
So I wonder how much the create stuff is gonna interact with redstone.
That's like something I'm curious about, you know?
As someone who knows a bit about redstone, not gonna say I'm an expert, but I definitely know my stuff.
Or new.
Give me that.
Some beef.
While that is happening, I should probably go get some coal.
Uh, this one.
Oh, I need ascension.
Oh, it's all coming back to me here.
It's crazy how muscle memory just stays within you, you know?
I may have to adjust my sensitivity a bit.
I feel like it's a bit...
Is it?
Ah, that's okay.
Maybe a little bit.
Options.
Controls?
Mouse settings.
A little faster.
Wait, I didn't heal that at all.
Okay.
I see more coal.
Coal is the stuff of life in this game.
And by the way, without coal, how are you gonna have an industrialization situation?
You know?
Which is what create is all about.
so I predict I need a shit ton of coal.
Okay.
All right.
Campfire, we don't need that.
There we go.
I'm actually gonna cook this as well.
I was actually...
You know what?
Okay, let's not talk too early.
Maybe there is a way to delete items later with create.
We'll have to see.
I was about to say, I don't want to be throwing things away like this.
They better have a fucking delete button in this mod.
That's all I'm saying.
Give me that.
Okay.
Now I'm pretty much ready.
We need to go caving real quick.
We gotta get iron.
Potentially even diamonds, actually, if we get lucky.
And then from then on, we can start doing things.
Actually, wait.
I need to make a shield.
Dude, what is the...
Wait, shield is...
iron...
and...
wood.
How have I not discovered that?
I'm losing my mind.
Oh, wait.
Maybe it's not called a shield?
Was it called something else?
Listen, I know this may sound like I'm suffering from something, but like, there's...
English is not my native language.
I don't remember if they were called exactly a shield, okay?
Because I feel like I only needed wood and some iron, but I can't see it, so I don't know.
I'm not beating the allegations, okay?
I understand.
Wait, what is that?
Is that a new one?
Oh, I need a better axe.
I think that's a new block.
What the hell?
Wait, I didn't realize they were going to put new blocks in the game.
Oh, shit.
Oh, no.
Oh, god.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Can I even get up?
Oh, he can't swim, right?
Yeah, too bad, buddy.
Uh, I actually need to have some stuff ready here, some food there.
Uh, yeah, we're going to have to kill him.
Actually, let me eat this.
I have no armor.
Yep, Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Very nice.
I think there's another skeleton.
Oh, my god.
Please.
Maybe I use the axe, actually.
The axe does more damage.
Dude, he...
Okay, first time doesn't count.
That's a general rule.
Dude, what the...
I didn't remember them doing that much damage.
I guess I didn't have armor, but holy shit.
Wow.
I do not remember them doing that much damage.
That doesn't even make any sense.
First one doesn't count.
There's always a grace of one.
Well, now I'm kind of fucked, though.
Oh, he's camping the spot.
I see my sword.
Get it!
Oh, go.
Oh, shit.
This is a bad idea.
Where's my...
sword?
Oh.
Is he coming?
Oh, my God!
Dude!
I hate this.
What a start, man.
It was going so well.
Like, are you kidding me?
The problem is, I can't ever get my items now.
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
It's a death spiral!
Okay, you know what?
Fuck it.
I'm not going to get my items.
I don't give a shit.
I'm leaving.
We're going to have to start over.
Sometimes you just got to retreat, you know, and lick your wounds.
Except that, you know, you didn't place very well.
It's okay.
Oh, man.
So, wait.
I don't...
The thing is, I would have had a shield if things made sense.
You know?
But things apparently don't make sense.
Maybe they changed the recipe for the shield with the mod.
Let me try and see.
It's definitely iron, and...
Is it not just wood?
Like, what?
Iron and wood.
I need to get some wood.
Oh, I can't believe it.
Man, what a setback, huh?
Goes to show, you can't ever underestimate the skeletons.
They will murder you.
If you let them.
And, you know what?
I was overconfident.
Because I'd played so much Minecraft.
I should have just, you know, not gone in that cave.
It was a bad idea.
It's fine, though.
Okay, let's start over here.
No.
Do this, please.
Thank you.
And now...
Like that.
And then we do...
It's good.
It's a new age.
I'm not gonna take any shortcuts.
We're going for this now.
We don't need a sword, because the axe will do.
I will take one of these, though.
From now on, we're playing so safe.
We're playing smart.
No more stupid decisions.
Oh, we also need a bed now.
I'm gonna go steal another bed.
Even though I could kill that sheep.
Actually...
You know what?
I'm gonna leave these sheep alive.
In case I need them later.
Yeah.
I think that's smart.
See, that's what I mean.
Smart decisions.
No acting on, you know, short-term gain.
This is for the long-term.
Long brain time.
Oh, wait.
They had a communal sleeping area.
Oh, that's actually a great start.
Ho, ho!
Amazing.
Did they have a chest thingy?
They didn't.
Um...
Okay.
Wait, this is...
For a second, I thought it was iron.
Like a block of iron.
But I don't recall exactly...
But it's similar looking.
But if it had been iron, it would have been genius.
Because then I would have had nine...
Uh...
Bars, you know?
Alright.
Sorry, I'm gonna have to come get this bed.
I know little Timmy's sleeping.
Oh, shit.
I'm sorry.
Did I just hurt you?
How did he just take damage?
Wait, did he take damage from falling down and hitting the floor?
Oh?
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
Maybe it's a mod thing.
Okay, let's actually go to bed.
Monster Hunter?
Oh.
Just an achievement.
Speaking of, let me actually see.
I can't believe I don't know the recipe for the shield.
It's actually kind of burning a hole in my brain.
Oh, wait.
We need food now.
See?
Now we go kill these sheep.
Because now we need them.
That's what I mean.
Now the zombies are in fire.
Uh, no.
Oh, there's a cow there.
I...
Oh, wait, actually.
No.
I need to make, uh, stone.
If I can get a furnace.
Look at that up there.
Doesn't that look like someone doing the, um...
The hand gesture with the...
With the, you know, with the thumb and the...
Pointy finger?
Making the little O sign up there?
Either that, or it's, like, some kind of, uh...
I don't know, four-legged creature.
This is the...
Mouth.
Or the eyes.
This is, like, its horn.
Like an iguana and its tail.
You see that?
I'm trying to prove to you guys that I have imagination.
And that I'm worthy of playing this mod.
I saw that shape over there.
And I immediately made the connection, you know?
Not everyone can do that.
Thank you.
Dude, the axe is actually just better than the sword.
They should buff the sword.
Okay.
Let's get some stone.
Dude, I have 11 raw beef now.
That is so...
I'm not gonna say it.
But it is pretty good.
I hate not being able to sprint.
Maybe these guys have a...
No, I'm not gonna destroy these houses.
Do I skip stone, though?
And go straight to iron.
Like a boss.
Hmm.
No.
See, that's a bad idea.
I'll take some of this.
Actually, I can't destroy that with, uh...
Wood.
The start is always rough.
Okay, guys.
Let's just say...
Clean slate.
The first two deaths didn't count.
It's from now on.
I just had to, you know, get over the initial hump of getting back into the game.
From now on.
Now.
From now on, I will not die a single time.
It's like when, uh...
When you have a student at an exam, you know?
When they come in and have to give an...
Give an oral presentation of 30 minutes.
You usually reserve, like, the first five minutes for the bullshit time.
Which means...
Whatever comes out of their mouth in the first five minutes doesn't count towards their grade.
Because everyone's nervous, you know?
That's what this is.
It's a real thing.
Um...
Oh, cool!
Good.
I need that for the oven.
God, it's so slow with...
Oh, wait.
Oh, good.
I have this though next.
I mean, you know...
I'm a little bit of a fancy hoe.
Because...
I'm used to diamond pickaxes, you know?
With all the enchantments.
All the bells and whistles.
This is...
Kind of painful for me, you know?
To have to stoop so low.
And use these primitive tools.
Okay.
Now we make a thingy.
I love...
I love making this when you go...
With the finger.
It's nice when you go...
It's one of those game...
Gameplay design decisions that are like genius, you know?
Having to make this...
Feels good.
Not sure if that was ever intended by whoever designed that, but...
Sure works.
Okay.
So while we wait for that, we're gonna...
What do you want?
Oh.
No, I'm not gonna fill my inventory with all kinds of shit.
We do have a bed.
What else do we need right now?
I don't want this smooth stone, actually.
Wait, what was the keybind for just...
Right.
But there was also one with like...
Control Q.
I forgot what the difference was.
Wait, there's no way this is...
Oh, wait.
Yeah, okay.
I was about to say, there's no way.
That's all I have discovered.
Hey, let's make a boat, actually.
Can you just make this one?
Good to have, right?
Oh, we don't have the gym mod!
I forgot that one.
It's gonna be no gym.
This is a no gym.
Unfortunately.
Damn.
How could I forget?
Hot air envelope?
That's gotta be new.
Uh, oh, wool.
Hmm.
I guess I can make that.
When I get some wool.
Uh, perhaps I should make some armor.
We're gonna get the iron...
Dude, uh...
Do I go back in that cave and teach them a lesson?
I really want to.
But this is like...
No mistake time now, right?
So, that's a bad idea.
Oh!
Torches!
We need torches.
Give me this.
Oh, that's exactly 64?
That's amazing.
What are the chances...
of that hitting exactly 64?
Okay.
Let's see if I can find some more coal while we wait.
Ah, give me this.
Thank you.
You come with me.
Okay, we really need to make a house.
And I don't want to use a house here, because it's...
I don't know.
I want my own house.
My own dwelling.
Oh!
We got iron!
That's huge, man.
I just skipped a bunch of progress.
Talk about getting lucky.
Give me some of this.
Yo, maybe there's more.
That is huge!
We can probably make, uh...
Like, a pickaxe and everything.
Put it in there.
Oh, wait.
I don't have any coal now.
I used it all on torches.
But it's a worthwhile investment.
You know, it's good to have torches.
And then we gotta figure out how to make that damn shield.
I can't believe I forgot how to make a shield!
You know what it is?
It's because...
It's like...
I never learned to drive manual, right?
I got put into an automatic car immediately.
Meaning that I always use the recipe book, right?
I don't actually know how to make things.
I am addicted to the recipe book.
But that's why it's there, right?
Uh, right.
What did I want to make?
Oh, yeah.
In.
And with four bars...
We can probably make...
Now, we can make one pickaxe.
But that's worth it.
Stone axe is actually good enough for combat.
As long as you jump and you get the crit on them, right?
Cheers.
Oh, maybe I should get some of this.
Use time effectively here.
I think I could be a speedrunner.
There's a bunch of new shit there.
Let me have a look.
Oops.
Or not?
Wait, what?
I could have sworn I just saw something that I don't recognize.
Oh, is it?
No.
Okay.
I'll find out.
Now I'm gonna go into the cave.
And watch this.
I've learned from my lessons.
Oh, man.
That looks scary, doesn't it?
I am gonna have to...
make a little path.
Oh, wait.
I can't destroy that, apparently.
Unless I can?
Now that I have stone?
What is this?
No, probably not, right?
It's gonna take forever.
Wait, let me see.
Shit.
Okay.
Oh, that's it?
Wow.
Also, I kind of want to look for...
Is that it?
And the side!
That's it for sure.
I recognize you.
But then I need to do something with it.
Should I polish it?
Probably not.
I mean, I could.
I could polish it.
But not today.
I'm gonna go up here.
Okay, so...
I know I said that I knew I needed andesite, but I'm actually not sure...
how to...
need the andesite.
You know what I mean?
Also, it's getting night.
We really should sleep.
Oh, no.
My bed is up there.
Why didn't I take it with me?
See, that's a rookie mistake right there.
Yeah, wait.
How did I even get down here?
That was a horrible idea.
Okay, from now on, we only explore nice caves.
This right here is a bad cave.
Alright, let's look for nice caves.
We also got some leather somehow.
I don't even know how we got that.
I just thought of something funny.
I'm not gonna say what it is, though.
Oh, I'm gonna kill all of you.
Daddy's gonna have stakes later.
This will actually fuel my exploration for quite a while.
Thank you.
I'm killing everyone.
They're mine.
Oops.
Go!
Oh, a one-shot!
Wait, I wonder if the hammer is in this one.
Huh.
Didn't that come out at the same time as, uh...
the pouches or whatever?
Hmm.
Maybe there's no hammer.
Kind of want a hammer.
Come here.
Wait!
That was also a spear at some point, apparently.
I never got to try that.
I think that was right after I, uh...
stopped, right?
Man, how far ahead is actual Minecraft of this right now?
I wonder.
Maybe actual Minecraft has more content than this.
You know?
Because they added so much stuff?
I'm kidding.
That's probably not true.
Okay, so...
See this area here?
This is what I was imagining with Oklahoma.
If you just ignore the hills.
Green, flat areas like this.
Yikes!
What's with the...
Oh, I have a boat.
Oh, now we're back in Minecraft, huh?
Let's sail.
To greener pastures.
Literally.
What the hell is that block up there?
That's sand?
And why is it up there?
It doesn't even make sense.
Oh, I...
Is this where I spawned?
Swampy area?
Oh, look at that.
Slid over there.
I bet there's zombies in there.
See, that's what I would call a bad cave.
Not a good one.
Wait, I see...
I see lava...
Going down into water.
Wait.
I'm trying to remember how...
Uh...
Shouldn't this make obsidian?
I'm brain farting.
I just don't remember.
I really don't remember.
I'm pretty sure that should make obsidian...
Because it's like flowing down into it.
Wait.
No.
No, no, no.
It's if you have lava...
And then...
Water comes down on it.
It's not the other way.
Right.
That's how it is.
I remember now.
Okay.
Actually eat these first.
Let's go this way.
See, this looks like a nice cape, doesn't it?
What is that?
That's new.
Limestone.
I'll take some of that.
It was that.
That's also new.
Oh, that's not new.
Calcite is...
Is a good old friend.
We remember calcite.
Wait.
Did I ever make the...
No, I didn't make my...
Iron pickaxe.
Let's make it.
Oh, it feels good.
Isn't it Iron pick?
Huh?
Doesn't even make sense.
Oh, I can feel the difference already.
Sweet mining speed.
I have missed you.
You know what?
I'm gonna lime my way up here.
People frown upon, you know, liming yourself upwards, but not me.
I'm okay with it.
I support it.
Can never get too much coal.
Wait.
Now I'm actually getting a little curious.
I need to see this.
So this is like an add-on...
Oh!
Yeah, this block is the one we had.
So that's the...
Yeah, okay.
So that's related to that.
Obtain some andesite alloy.
Now, let me, uh...
I'm just gonna get a bunch of materials and we're gonna experiment.
I also need more iron.
Oh, maybe I can get this now.
Huh?
Raw sink?
Whoa!
That's new.
Sink.
An andesite...
Who makes an andesite wall?
That's for losers.
Am I right?
Uh, what else unlocked?
What?
Concrete!
That's new!
Wait, is it?
Maybe that's not new.
You wanna play a game of...
Is that new?
I'll be here all day.
Maybe it would make sense to play this after you've played a little bit of Minecraft, like, right before, you know?
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Some of these obscure blocks that I never used, I don't know, you know?
Uh, that is definitely sand and sandstone.
Oh my god.
My movement is, like, terrible!
I used to be, like, all over the place, you know?
Like a pro.
Parkouring.
Nowadays, not so much.
Ooh, let's get some more of this.
It's probably gonna be a big resource.
Together with andesite, you know?
Save this as well.
Um, yeah.
As long as you don't go into a cave, you cannot actually die.
Oh, yeah.
See, now that I know what's important in Minecraft, I'm gonna pick up the most important stuff as I go, you know?
Okay, so I spawned over there.
Let me actually just do this real quick.
Just so we have a respawn.
Dude, what is it with the crimes here?
Are you actually kidding me?
There's a portal.
Let's go loot the chest.
Maybe we get something good.
Yo, I wonder if they added new stuff in, uh...
in the nether and shit, you know?
I'm actually so excited just to see what's new.
I have to remember to use keybinds like this.
Give me all that.
Dude, I'm thinking about...
the fact that you can apparently make a car.
And I'm just sitting here thinking...
How?
How...
How is that gonna work?
Without looking janky as hell.
Like, I'm...
I'm ready to be surprised, but...
Like, in a good way.
But I just don't see it.
In a game that works this way?
Hey!
Sweet!
Obsidian as well.
Very nice.
Okay.
Golden apple.
That's nice.
Good stuff.
What about...
the frickin' shield?
Can we make it?
What is it?
Oh!
Oh, I never smelted it!
It's...
Right!
I really thought I did.
I was, like, convinced I smelted it.
But I was right, you know?
It was iron and wood.
I had it.
I know these things.
I may not know them precisely, but I know about them.
What was I doing?
Oil!
Let's make a shield.
So we need some wood.
More wood.
And maybe I go into the nether.
Just to get, like, crazy materials to start with.
It can really boost me, you know?
I'm actually gonna take this as well.
Use it for my own.
Ooh!
Ah, but I can't grab this without, uh, diamond pickaxe.
Let's not even worry about it.
I have missed Minecraft music.
I wonder if there's new music with the mod.
Stop that.
Now we turn this into these.
God, I hate my inventory already.
This is...
Kids, look away!
Okay?
This is temporary.
Uh, why did I just pick this up?
Yeah!
We are back!
I will never die again!
This is the moment...
where my luck shifts.
And we shall ascend to the heavens...
in automobiles!
It's gonna be fun.
And also a little dangerous.
Because I don't know how to drive.
I actually don't.
I don't have a driver's license.
So, yeah.
It's gonna be...
probably a...
catastrophe.
Uh, oh!
It's actually getting dark.
We should, uh, just sleep.
I was about to say, let's make a shelter and shit, but no!
Just sleep!
Come on!
Why you gotta make it hard on yourself?
Doesn't this look weird?
The way the colors sort of blend there?
Maybe that's new.
That doesn't look...
correct.
I do remember some things.
Okay, it's way too hilly here.
We gotta keep going to find the perfect spot.
Yo, we need to find a spot that is next to a nice cave.
So that we can go on, uh, excursions like that, you know?
Maybe actually here.
This almost looks like a quarry-type place.
And we need some armor.
Actually, we need iron armor.
Speaking of iron...
I have spotted it.
This is a bad cave.
Got it.
We need to find, like, a huge chunk of iron, like we did that one time.
We're talking, like, insane amounts of it.
Hey!
Okay.
Those are kind of rare.
We need this for a zoomer.
And we also need to find the little crystals down below.
Actually, I should get that fast.
Maybe here?
No, that's not a cave.
They call me the one coal man.
I just take one coal wherever I go and leave rest.
This is my style.
That is it!
That's the spot!
Right there!
We made it!
How much you want to bet there's a nice cave system right over there?
Even have wildlife.
Ooh!
Look at this!
I see a creeper down there.
And I even see, like, a...
Waterfall.
Which is a natural elevator.
It's going to soften the blow when I fall.
Or drop.
What?
I thought I could set fire to the sheep!
Why doesn't that work?
Huh?
I thought you could do that!
Am I crazy?
Maybe it's only the...
Flint and Tinder.
I don't remember.
Oh, that's a...
It's an animal.
It's the fucking, you know...
The ones that Mexicans ride on in the 1800s.
Okay.
This is a great spot.
I'm going to make a house here.
Let's get some wood.
As a kid, I used to make that noise all the time.
The...
Eee!
And my mom...
My mom would...
Hated it.
Like, I would drive her crazy.
I would, like...
Say it for, like, a minute.
You know?
Back and forth.
The top of my lungs.
I was a real nasty piece of shit.
I don't know why I did that.
Dude, she must have thought I was, like...
He's special.
There's something going on with him.
If I had a kid that did that, you know?
I don't know.
Not good signs.
That's all I'm saying.
Okay.
This is actually not a good spot.
Whoa!
Oh, yikes.
Disgusting.
Not the view you want to have.
I can...
I can take care of that later.
Because apparently we can fly up there.
Right?
So we're going to fly up there.
And we're going to take care of it.
Dude, I don't know.
How is that even going to work?
How...
Wait.
Hold on.
How is that even going to work?
Like, that sounds janky as hell.
I'm not even kidding.
I need to see this in action.
Ah, wait.
I actually don't want to destroy these trees.
Because if this is my home...
It also looks to...
Needs to look nice.
Oh, we actually have a forest over there.
Ooh, that's perfect.
Maybe I'll do that real quick.
It's midday.
We have time.
Also, my inventory is shit.
That's okay.
I could also make my home over there among the trees.
Wouldn't be the worst idea.
But I need to go caving.
And it needs to happen soon.
This is, like, the big thing.
So we can get diamonds.
We can get iron.
We can just, you know, get started.
For real.
Because right now, I'm just sort of gallivanting.
Not achieving much here.
Oh, god.
These cows I'm going to breed.
It'll happen later.
Focus on farming and living off the land this time around.
No more, you know, weird trips to the supermarket and getting one item at a time.
Oh.
That's a nice looking cave.
I feel like I've been here.
Whoops.
This is the one I'm going to explore.
Let's make a temporary hut here.
Ultimate temporary hut.
Forty.
That's enough.
It's not pretty.
It's functional.
Okay.
This is all we need to do.
Let's make a treehouse!
I've never made it.
Before.
Just a quick, dirty treehouse functional hut.
I'm a changed man.
I'm doing the things I've always wanted to.
And then we need a ladder up here.
Okay.
How do I make a ladder?
Right.
Sticks.
Sticks and stones.
Mindjack.
Oh.
Leave it.
Six.
And you know what?
If I do this, yo.
Treehouse is actually amazing.
Because then monsters can't get you either.
Right?
And if they can't climb up here, you don't even need a proper roof.
Look at this!
I can sit here with my bow.
Oops.
Put that there.
Maybe we need like a little...
Oh, I have an idea.
I know I said functional and not pretty, but we're just gonna quickly make it pretty.
Ah!
Not bad, eh?
I like this.
This is neat.
Ah, I'm a little worried.
Maybe zombies could come in here.
Could happen.
Not entirely.
Okay, let's deposit.
Ah, calcite.
Ross.
This is crazy.
Maybe this is actually...
No, that's new for sure.
I was like, I've seen this before, but I don't think I have.
Now we need the oven.
There you go.
Put in the money and this stuff.
We have enough torches.
Actually, you know what?
I've learned my lesson.
You never have enough torches.
There's never enough torches.
Ah, I should also cook this.
I guess.
This can go in here.
We don't need this wooden shit.
Uh, kill.
Neither do we need that.
I don't need these.
Okay, we got 11 stakes.
I think it's a good start.
Oh, we have flint and steel.
Very nice.
Always bring wood with you down into the caves.
I actually forgot why.
Why is that the case?
I just remembered the rule that I made.
That's good.
Oh, let's bring the boat as well so we can, you know, drop down and not take damage.
Speed running strats right there.
Thank you.
This one I can't eat.
I think I need to...
Wait, can I eat it?
I can, okay.
I'm not gonna eat it though.
That's kind of important.
You go in there.
No, actually, you come with me.
Oh, you want to bring wood so you can make more, you know, fiery sticks.
Let's go!
Let's go on an expedition.
The first one.
A proper one.
Let's go to bed real quick before night falls.
It's about to be night.
Hold on.
I gotta angle my AC.
Oh yeah, that's amazing.
Oh my god.
I have joined the Americans in celebration of ACs.
It is truly life-changing.
And everyone should have an AC.
It needs to be a human right.
Ah!
Oh my god!
The footsteps scared me!
You little bitch!
Oh.
Yeah, that's how we do it.
Chances!
Dude, I didn't even take a single point of damage just now.
Oh my god!
It's ugly!
I hate my fucking trio!
What is even that?
That is the worst trio of all time.
Wait, how do I get these letters?
Oh, they came back to me!
Fuck.
Get out of here.
Can't believe this.
Oh, we're out in flesh.
Oh, and now it's night.
Now we go sleep.
Sleep.
Look at all these achievements.
It's the start of the game.
So, you know, you accumulate a lot real quick.
There you go.
That's it!
Expedition 1.
Oh, you asshole.
You know what, actually?
Yes.
I would like some gunpowder.
Yeah.
Now we got the rockets.
We gotta get the elytra fast, by the way.
Because, I mean, once you've elytra-ed, you can never un-elytra-ed, you know?
And look at this.
Immediately we get lucky.
Great start.
And now we take it slow.
I already hear...
Oh.
Not today, thank you.
Dude, shields are so good.
Hold on.
Is my brightness all the way up?
Brightness.
Nothing changed.
Oh.
It did change a little bit.
Oh my god.
Oh!
You gotta be careful when you don't have proper armor.
I see more iron.
Oh my god.
Let's get this.
Wait, I feel like I've seen this before.
This was a part of the game.
This is not actually new.
Am I gaslighting myself right now?
This is...
kinda familiar to me.
But also not at the same time.
I like 50-50, I guess.
Give me some of this.
What was the reason why I wanted this?
Oh yeah, experience.
We want experience so we can get enchantments.
Dude, the progression is actually...
Just in the vanilla base game...
It's actually so amazing when you think about it.
Already level 8 too.
That's the first time I looked at my levels...
Since I started.
How crazy is that?
Yo, this is looking really nice.
I mean, except for the lava, obviously.
But it's just so...
Filled with light, you know?
No monsters?
Good times.
I don't remember if I ever tried this...
But I don't think I can actually ride a boat in lava.
I'm pretty sure you cannot do that.
Otherwise, I would have more memories of doing that.
Is there a safe path down?
Hmm.
Kinda.
But I need to make it so that I can easily get back up.
Oh no.
Actually, no.
I'm not gonna do that.
I'm not gonna do it.
Oh, this one we can block off.
We don't need to see that.
Is this deep slate?
There we go.
Blocked.
Oh my god, that takes a long time.
I see gold as well.
I wanna grab everything.
And I...
Yeah.
But iron is the most important.
We already have a lot.
21.
Good start.
I thought I could jump on this.
Imagine I died just now.
That would have been so pathetic.
Nice.
And I know the physics, so it's never gonna reach me here.
Oh, nice.
Heck yeah.
Compass time.
Oh, redstone components, my beloved.
Um, wait.
No.
Oh man, I thought this was a proper cave.
This is really the end of it?
I was looking forward to some diamond action.
Whatever.
I will take that gold.
Oh, can I...
Oh, wait.
I have a bow?
Oh, it's from the zombies.
Whoa!
Ah!
Shit!
Fuck!
That was the easiest jump of my life.
How did I fail that?
Spicable.
Embarrassing.
I'm trying to show off a little bit, and I'm just making a fool of myself.
Will you stop burning?
Hello?
Thank you.
Dude, I really need some ascension blocks here.
I'm losing my mind.
Oh, wait.
This is gonna make them...
No, it's not.
And there we go.
Oh!
Sweet!
Diamonds!
Oh my goodness!
The mother load has been located.
Oh, there's more than one!
Wow!
Okay, we are totally back.
There we go.
Good stuff.
Oh.
Oh, you're spawning in here.
We got a rotator.
Ah, wait.
Leave it.
In case I want to abuse that later, somehow.
Okay, so there was this method.
Oh, yeah, fishing.
We should do some of that.
One bread.
I will steal this.
Thank you.
Iron.
Dude, we can actually make a pickaxe and an axe now.
This is insane.
Great start.
I'm so proud of myself for not going back into that cave with the skeleton.
You know, I went the other way.
I turned my cheek around.
And I said, not today.
Or however that saying goes.
Also, this is deep start?
Yep.
Okay.
Something I need to keep in mind as well.
Is that I may need to pick up, like, all kinds of different blocks.
Just to reveal recipes, right?
So who knows what's going to happen.
You have a name tag as well.
Oh, this is where I was.
Okay.
This was a great little side cave.
Very nice.
I may actually grab some more.
Since I'm here.
Good.
We found a little bit of everything.
Let's get out.
Nah.
I was hoping we would find some, um...
Uh, you know, the crystal thingies.
I forget the name of it.
If I can make a zoomer.
Let's actually go home...
...and start progressing.
We're gonna try and build as much as we can from the...
...from the recipe book.
Wait, is that...
I need that.
Okay, good.
This is the spot over here.
But I actually went over here to get some wood, so let me get that real quick.
Oh, wait.
I made a treehouse, didn't I?
Right.
It's over here.
It's very easy to spot because it is ugly.
It is the nastiest treehouse in existence.
I actually can't...
I want to burn it down.
After this, because this is a disgrace.
I mean, it looks nice from here.
But from down there...
Not good.
Okay.
Let's cook some...
Iron.
Eat this.
And let's have a look, shall we?
First things first.
Sticks.
I think I had some...
Oh, wait.
Bring this up here.
It's getting a little cramped in this treehouse.
No sticks, but I can make them.
It's a new age.
Two of these.
Oh, yeah!
And then...
Whoop!
Look at that.
Isn't that just the prettiest thing ever?
Oh, it was to throw out the whole thing.
Yeah, I remember now.
Good.
Now we have a lot of this, which means we're going to make iron armor!
Whoops.
This is such a good start.
Should I make it?
Oh, we got to make a bow, but I don't have any arrows.
Yet.
Oh, I'm definitely making that.
And...
You know what?
I'm a changed man, guys.
I'm actually never going to equip a sword again.
I'm going to have one extra slot here now, because the axe is my sword.
This is the new me.
Fuck swords.
We don't care about him.
Bucket is good to have.
Yeah.
I can make a block of raw sink.
So all of this is familiar.
I think I need to do this thing with andesite.
Wait.
Oh, I was about to say snipers can crawl up here, but spiders...
Actually, this is a problem right here.
They can get to me.
Can you actually get up here?
Oh, you can't get up here, huh?
You suck!
Wish I could have, like, tomahawks and throw this axe right into his face.
Imagine that.
Okay, so we actually have a double chest situation going now.
I already hate everything about my sword here.
I mean, except for the diamond stuff.
Okay, so let's see if there's any...
What can I do with my andesite?
I'm just going to make a little bit of everything.
But not yet.
We're going to tear down this treehouse.
When we're done making this.
Let's get some armor going.
Helmet.
Lex.
I thought it said shut up.
Or a second.
Okay, put that on.
Nice.
I think we'll have enough to get a full suit of armor.
Which is awesome.
We got andesite here.
I could make arrows!
No, I can't.
I need feathers for that.
Why is that in there?
Now give me...
What am I missing?
Boots and chest.
Oh, fuck.
Sleep.
He's not going to blow up below me.
That's not how that works.
And they can't climb, so...
See ya.
Let's get rid of this one as well.
Do I care about the name tag at this point?
No.
We're going to focus on the most essential stuff.
We're not going to carry this around.
We'll get the opportunity for that later.
We don't need this either.
So I'm going to take the most important stuff with me here.
Like, these things are important.
The dirt is important too, for ascension reasons.
Did I just...
I just destroyed the chest.
Dude, I miss pouches!
I need pouches!
Shit.
How did I ever survive without it?
That's my question.
Thank you.
Actually, let's quickly make that last piece of armor.
There we go.
We're going to keep this because we can disenchant it and get experience.
I'm out of here.
See you later.
Nobody shall see what that treehouse looked like.
Wish I had my zoomer right now.
What is it called?
The...
You know?
Monocle extension device.
I think it's time!
And I didn't get the wood I came here for.
Let's get a little bit more wood.
First we wood, and then we do other things.
God, I hate my inventory.
Okay, we get rid of the dirt.
Ascension is not important at this stage.
But it will be later.
Oh, it's a bad tree!
Siamese trees.
Maybe I'll focus more on mushrooms as well this time around.
I don't think I gave mushrooms a fair shake.
You know, ever.
I think the first house I'm making here...
It is going to be a little...
We're going to make it semi-pretty.
I'm not going to spend too long on it.
But I need it to be a little, you know, presentable for my own sanity.
If I get another treehouse like that going, I...
I will die.
Mentally.
I can't handle it.
Oh no, why did I do this?
Wait, I just remembered a way to do this faster.
Saplings.
Oh, but I don't have bone meal.
So never mind.
It's like some advanced stuff.
Okay.
Now we make house.
There's also a cave here.
So I went down into that one before.
This is an option.
Let's make it right here.
A little more this way.
Down here on the lowest part.
Let's be smart about this.
Nice.
No.
One, two.
Wait, is that new?
I can just put a block on top of this grass without destroying it first.
I feel like usually you have to do that.
It's gonna be a little narrow down here.
I just didn't want a square house, you know?
Like the tiniest bit of...
Um, what's the word?
Variation is good, you know?
I don't even know how I'm doing...
What?
Okay.
This corner doesn't have a frickin' pillar.
Because I don't understand it.
We don't need a pillar there.
It's fine.
Wait, this looks wrong as well.
There's something wrong about this.
Yeah, there we go.
Oh, wait, this is wrong.
Why is this so...
Dude, I need to find, like, a surefire way to make a foundation.
I am not good at making those.
There we go, we did it.
Boom.
And now...
Whoop.
Have it.
Whoopsie-daisy.
There we go.
Missed it.
Precision gaming.
Whoop.
And now...
We make more wall.
I think I have exactly enough wood for this as well.
Which is amazing.
Ah, we may not have enough.
We don't need a roof yet.
This is just a start.
Bit more.
Nice.
Now we get these up here.
You see how much these pillars add to the look of the house?
Like, they almost don't do anything, but they do so much at the same time.
You know what I mean?
It's a cheap win.
And now we have a home.
In fact...
We can actually make a roof.
We have enough.
We just need one more here.
And then we, um...
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
Yep, that's fine.
This is good.
I have a better idea.
I have an idea for a roof.
It's gonna look amazing.
It does not involve triangular patterns.
I'm totally over that.
Keep it simple, but nice.
You know what I mean?
Oops.
And we save a whole row of blocks as well.
Affordable housing.
Boom!
Lights!
Now it's a home.
Then we need a door.
Doctor.
Door.
That's actually kind of easy.
Nice!
Wait, what's this?
I don't like that.
Okay, it's not the greatest thing ever.
I admit.
But it'll do.
For now.
Flooring.
We are not really interested in that.
Are we?
Maybe we are, actually.
Quick flooring session.
No.
You know what?
Actually, we keep the floor as dirt.
Because it's like...
It's a design decision.
But we're gonna have it one layer lower, you know?
Just to make it look nice.
Contemporary style, right?
What are the...
Stairs.
That's what that's called.
Boink!
Nice!
Now we need a chest.
Doink, doink.
And now we fill it.
This is the standard practice.
We just put everything in first.
And then we take what we need.
What do I need?
This one goes...
Uh...
There.
And then we have a crafting table somewhere.
It's outside.
And now it's raining.
Boom!
Just in time for the weather, huh?
How cozy is this?
Put a nice bed there.
Doink!
Fill that up.
Stoke the fire!
As they say.
Let's start cooking some...
Gold and stuff.
Mmm...
Give me that one.
Guess I keep the sticks as well.
Torches.
Iron.
Do I keep the iron?
Should I make anything with iron?
I don't know.
Okay, but let's have a look.
Uh...
Yep, okay.
Let's do...
Andesite stuff.
I don't know...
What I need here.
You know what?
Let's look here.
Obtain some andesite alloy.
Creates most important resource.
What is an alloy made of?
Metal.
Right?
Gold alloy.
Iron alloy.
Alloy it with things.
It's like reinforcing the thing, right?
Make it sturdier.
Sturdier rocks!
Hey!
Exactly.
Like, this looks insane.
You can combine wheels and stuff, you know?
Assemble a windmill of maximum strength.
How is that even going to work?
Apply andesite alloy to a stripped wood, creating a basic casing for your machines.
The thing is, though, if I don't have the recipe for it, it means I haven't found the thing I need.
I need to make a bow and get some arrows, honestly.
Maybe we just go explore a little bit first.
Get some random material so we can really experiment.
In terms of food, we actually have 20 steaks, which is very respectable.
That is enough for a good session of caving.
Bring that as well.
There are chickens outside I could kill and get some feathers from.
But I'm not sure I should do it.
Bring the pocket as well.
Always good to have on an adventure.
Sorches.
Dirt.
Wait, maybe I need to...
Hold on.
Oh.
Oh, okay.
Maybe...
Yeah, maybe I need gold.
I'm looking at the...
Okay.
Cook this one, too.
I think I'm just going to go explore again.
Yeah.
Actually, cook this before I go.
Just to save time.
Let's go.
Not during the night, though.
Okay, I'm bringing this bed.
I really should have two beds.
Oops.
That's it.
Oh, there's one.
All right, let's go.
Now, I was thinking, maybe I'll bring another shovel, because, you know, iron shovel is not really that nice.
I mean, it's fine, but...
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Are you ready?
Oh, no, never mind.
I was about to perform the bucket trick.
Actually, I can still do it.
Let's see if I got it.
Guys, should I jump over and do it down there?
I can't even do it.
I'm going to...
We're playing safe.
That's just...
Of course I wasn't going to do that.
Come on.
What do you think I am?
Kind of psycho?
Wait, this music is new!
I don't think I've ever heard this track.
Am I crazy?
Come here.
Fully armored.
Pretty soon we're going to have full diamond armor.
This is a nice cave.
Oh, I forgot to try and smelt this!
Ooh, that's probably the whole frickin' trick, isn't it?
Oh.
Okay, I have a clear goal when I come home.
That's obviously what it is.
I know what to do now.
Nice.
But getting more iron...
Is also nice.
I don't remember putting this torch there!
What the fuck?
Like, it was way higher than I remember putting.
So weird.
What the...
Shit!
Come on!
Oh my god, I got hit.
I'm trying to do a no-hit run.
I failed.
So I saw something crazy in that cave over there.
We're going to investigate, of course.
Not before I do this.
Wait, what is that?
That's new.
That is completely new.
Wait, what am I...
Oh, oh!
Ah-ha!
Look at you, you little frickin' bastard.
Oh, I'm so good at dealing with you.
Didn't even get close to me.
Put some lights here.
Yeah, that's...
I don't even know what that is.
Viridium.
Makes sense that it's green.
You know?
Let's just get a bunch.
It's probably pretty good.
Let's get, like, one stack.
Hey, maybe this is hiding something.
You know how, um, those crystals are hidden beneath this outer layer?
Oh, actually, yeah.
This.
Is this actually what it is?
Wait, this is different.
Wait, why does it...
You're seeing this, right?
This is brighter than this.
But it's apparently the same...
It's like a lighting thing.
I guess.
I have to...
I have to try and dig down here and see what's going on down there in Boston.
And if I can get those crystals, even better.
What's that?
I think it's andesite.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Let's not go that way.
So there's nothing down.
Let's try to go...
Well, it almost...
It almost looks like...
Oh.
It looks a little...
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Careful.
Oh, I would have fallen if I did that!
I caught myself!
I'm a changed man.
Imagine.
I had a moment of clarity.
Okay, that's just funny.
That is just funny, actually.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Oh, that's so stupid.
What is wrong with me?
I was all proud of myself, you know?
I'll get this.
Man, this pickaxe is still quite not my tempo.
It's dragging.
We need more.
Speed.
Let me try and go up.
Also, I gotta remember I have a drink.
I actually bought some wine as well.
Just to celebrate.
I'm gonna open that soon.
Okay, I don't know what the hell is going on here.
But, uh, it's above my pay grade.
Let's keep moving.
Not sure what's happening with that viridium.
That's a dead end.
Dude, I'm actually...
I'm so...
It's kind of crazy how much I haven't discovered yet of this.
I really was expecting to just immediately be, like, bombarded by a million different things, you know?
And that would have been the case if I hadn't, you know, taken my grubby little hands and massaged things in a way where...
Let's just say you don't want to know how the sausage is made.
Or at least a lot of people don't want to know.
The sausage is good, though.
But they don't want to know how it's made.
It's just how it is.
Get away from me!
The question is, should I be investing in sync here?
Should I put everything into sync?
This could pay off big, you know?
If this is actually the key that I'm missing...
This could kickstart myself into the industrial age of create.
By the way, I'm not keeping track of where I am.
So I'm getting lost on purpose right now, is what I used to call this.
So when I need to leave, I just go up.
Because that way I don't have to worry about, you know, the path I'm taking and all that.
Oh!
Oh, there's more.
Wait!
Maybe I can make sync armor?
Because I just realized, I have no idea what is even being added with these mods here.
Like, that could be whole new armors and stuff.
Maybe...
Dude, what if there's an AK-47 or, like, the equivalent?
I mean, industrialization?
Maybe there's a gun?
I want a gun.
So bad.
I just want to blast these fools with pistolas, you know?
And, uh, what is the word for those?
Blunderbusses!
I want a blunderbuss!
Maybe I can get that.
Oh!
What do you think you're doing?
Yeah.
Gotta stay away.
Okay.
It seems like, uh, whatever, uh, is going on with this, it's plenty.
So I don't have to worry about getting that.
Oh!
Didn't mean to fall down!
Okay.
That's my first creeper explosion.
Uh, maybe I should have brought my bed down here now that I think about it.
Because if I die now, I cannot...
Okay, see, yeah.
This is actually why it's not a good idea to go get lost on purpose.
Because if you die, you cannot actually get your shit back.
That's the one thing I forgot.
But if it wasn't for that detail, it's actually a genius idea what I'm doing, you know?
It's just that one little wrinkle.
Hey!
Explode for me!
Thanks!
Talk about industrialization.
I'm blasting my way through these blocks.
Dude, I'm gonna industrialize so hard later!
I just got a little scared because the fucking lights go out!
Sorry.
I overreacted.
It's on me.
At least we're getting a lot of iron.
Imagine it turns out...
that I can somehow make iron, like, really easily.
Wait, what the f...
Is this...
crimsite?
Guess I'll take that.
No idea what to do with that.
Also, not a lot of recipes were revealed with that just now, so maybe it's not super useful.
I don't know what's happening here.
I see more iron.
I need that.
Good.
Let's go deeper.
I can't believe I haven't found diamonds yet down here.
Really gotta be careful, though.
Dude, what if there's new monsters?
I didn't even think about that.
Oh, shit.
I'm actually ready to get jump-scared now.
I'm, like, gaslighting myself into being scared before it even happens now.
Holy...
I should not be going up.
I should be going down.
Man, I wish I had my zoom.
Gotta find one of those deposits.
Oh, that's a bat.
I thought it was, like, a new enemy.
For a second, I was, like, hmm...
Maybe it's modded to walk towards me and bite me now, you know?
That would be so funny.
I wanna go deeper.
So I kinda came from here.
Here.
Let's go here.
Also, still 18 stakes.
We're doing wonderful on that.
I really don't wanna die now.
Imagine I lose all this.
But I can't leave without diamonds, man.
I need at least a little bit.
Just to taste.
Just to have that protection.
In case stuff happens.
Because you don't know.
Let's not go that way.
Dude, I can't wait to get home and try the sink.
Makes me sound like that's a middle-aged man who bought a new sink for his house.
You know?
And he just can't wait to try it.
Like such an old person thing to care about.
I am actually like that, you know?
I get excited about new vacuum tech.
I watch technology connections and learn about fans.
And ACs, you know?
This is the stage I'm at in my life.
And I'm not saying it's a bad thing.
Oh!
I'm going.
God!
That was way too risky for no reason!
What am I doing?
Dude, for some reason I remembered being able to just make a quick air hole.
But that's not the case, it seems.
Fuck off with that medicine.
I actually got so angry just now because of that.
I'm stuck.
Alright, I'm going up.
No diamonds this time around.
And it's not in my cards.
We're going to have to podcast a little bit here.
What it is, what it is.
Oh!
Okay.
Oh, that was kind of a scary sight.
I was ready to, uh...
climb my way out of there.
Or dig my way out.
Ascend with a gorb.
I'm not even that far down.
And you know how I know?
Because I haven't gone far down.
That's so dumb.
I'm going to use this gravel.
Let's use the tough.
Guys...
Day or night?
I say...
Day.
Because days promise...
progress.
Yo, I'm...
I'm right back here!
That's amazing!
Wow!
Almost like it's calculated.
And there's my bed!
Incredible.
Embedible!
Oh, wait.
Hold on.
I actually...
There's still something I need to do here.
Before I go.
And then I'll...
I'll prove to you that it's day outside.
Just gotta get a couple more things.
I gotta...
I gotta look this way in case there's monsters coming after me on my way out, you know?
Just gotta watch my back here.
Make sure there's nothing in the floor coming out to grab me.
What do you think coming out of the floor to grab me?
Come on!
Fuck!
Show thyself!
Ah!
It's night!
Oh, shit!
Oh, man.
I hate that.
Ha ha ha ha!
Oh, we got...
Okay.
Are you ready for sink?
I can't wait to install this sink.
We're gonna open up a whole new world of possibilities, baby.
We also have an enderman.
Why do they spin?
Okay, you know what?
See you later.
I'm going into my house.
Fuck!
Can't follow me.
And now I'm safe!
Let's slap down a bit.
All right.
Uh...
Do-do-do-do-do-do.
Oh, wait.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
That's new.
Oh, my God.
Hold on.
We got...
Oh, what's that?
That's a nugget.
Does that look different than normal?
Looks different.
Wait, I saw, like, a weird double door.
Why is it not showing?
At some point, I can unlock things in this book.
Why can't I see this...
double door?
Wait, am I blind?
Hold on.
This is all, so if it's not showing in that one, it's not showing anywhere.
Okay, I don't know.
Oh, maybe it's via some kind of crafting thingy.
Not a loom, but, like, the equivalent of a loom.
You know what I mean?
Okay, let's, uh, take the sink.
Okay, man!
Oh, this is gonna be good.
A sink ingot.
Why does it look like that?
Sink flapjacks?
Sink nuggets?
Oh, this one was flashing.
What was that?
There it is, baby!
That's the one we need!
Very nice!
Okay, now we're cooking, baby!
I knew it was the sink.
Very good.
Okay, what's that?
White tablecloth?
Wait, why do you need alloys for that?
That doesn't even make sense.
Attach to the front of an encased fan to distribute its effect on entities in all directions.
Oh!
For some reason, I read this as muzzle.
And then, like, putting a muzzle on entities so they can't...
I don't know what I thought.
It's a nozzle.
That's different.
Hand crank?
Kinetic stress capacity is small.
What is this sci-fi?
Cart assembler?
Okay, we are cooking right now, guys.
We are on the way.
Piston extension pole.
Are you saying that I can have a piston go...
longer?
Because that is crazy.
If that's the case.
Package filter.
Sorry.
Matches packaged items by their targeted address?
Be used in filter slots of creates components.
When R-collect opens the configuration interface.
Excuse me?
Block of sync?
Wooden bracket?
I'm not building anything yet, because I just want to see here.
Decorate your shafts, cockwheels, and pipes with a cozy and wooden bit of reinforcement.
It's so weird being able to see a description of an item in Minecraft.
You know?
I don't know how I feel about that.
I mean, it's fine like this.
So, what is that one?
Radial chassis.
That doesn't have a description on it.
What can I make?
No, actually, keep it like this, and then let's look again.
Slowly.
Let's make a hand crank.
Right, okay, so this is the system.
You can ponder on things.
Yeah.
Let me see.
I've seen this system for one thing, called a...
some kind of press.
Okay, let me see.
Hand cranks can be used by players to apply rotational force manually.
Okay.
Hold right-click to rotate it counterclockwise.
Yo, is that a gauge?
Sneak and hold right-click to rotate it clockwise.
I am so impressed with, like, this right here.
Like, this looks insane.
Comfy reading.
What?
Right.
Okay.
This is some kind of gauge.
Subject of this scene.
0.5 kilopascal...
Gerald.
I don't know what that unit is.
I have no idea.
Kinetic sources.
Wait, can I actually use this?
Like this?
Oh!
Wait.
Whoa!
Wait, that is...
There's, like, a weird wind in my ears when I do it.
Wait, why won't it go the other way?
I'm sneaking.
Oh, wait, I'm not.
Wrong button.
I see, I see.
I get it.
Wait, can I...
Wait, that's...
Okay, wait, hold on.
Slowly.
Let's take it slow.
What else can I...
So, what is it?
What do I need here?
Okay, so we need more anticide alloys.
We need sink nuggets.
We need a lot of sink nuggets.
Nug me!
Oh, yeah.
Alloy.
Wait, I have more, uh...
Oh, I knew I should have grabbed more anticide.
Shit.
Okay, now we have a lot of these.
I need to clean up my inventory.
I'm getting an ulcer just looking at it.
Verid...
Yeah, just put it in there.
Now, let's see what I can make.
Okay, see, the problem here is...
I would love to make this.
But it's like...
What even is a cart assembler?
Right?
Basin.
Let's make a basin.
Here we go.
Yeah!
Okay.
Let's see.
A basin can hold items and fluids for processing.
After a processing step, basins try to output below to the side of them.
When a valid component is present, then basin will show an output faucet.
A number of options are applicable here.
Yeah, we're gonna make belts!
I wanna make a belt so bad.
Outputs will be caught.
Okay.
Can I pause this?
Pause button!
Okay, this pauses.
So that's definitely like a gear.
This is the press?
Isn't that depressing?
Um...
Alright.
Let me see what else I can make.
Gantry shaft?
Oh, I love gantry shafts, man!
That's like my favorite...
What is this?
Copper diving boots.
What?
A pair of heavy boots allowing for better traversal of the ocean floor?
Wielder descends more quickly in liquid.
It grants the ability to walk and jump on the water?
Wielder also is no longer affected by mechanical belts.
Dude, that sounds amazing.
Whoa!
This is like gameplay-altering...
Uh...
What do you call it?
Splash zone here.
Holy shit!
Now we unlock something new with the table there.
Smithing table.
Wait.
This is just like, um, Zelda.
You know?
That is actually so cool.
I like that.
Can't wait to try that.
Does that mean I can also mine quick- Shh, shh, shh, shh, under water?
Because that would be...
Top tier.
Shaft.
Shaft!
Neurons are dancing.
Um...
Shafts will relay rotation in a straight line.
Okay, I see.
And then you can crank it with a hand crank.
So I guess this is like a gauge for how fast something is rotating.
Would be my guess.
You know, we should have a chest just for this.
This is not what we're doing.
I need to make a chest...
For specialized components.
Like that.
This is for the new stuff.
Um...
Let's put this in here.
I have too much shit right here.
Also, we can...
Oh, this is still cooking.
Nice.
I guess we don't need all of these sink nuggets right now.
This is gonna be like new...
Uh...
No.
Just put everything in here.
This is all the new...
New stuff.
Then this goes in there.
This hurts my brain, okay?
If you look at this and go...
I'm right there with you, okay?
I'm right there with you.
This is horrible.
And we're gonna figure out something.
Sooner or later.
For now, though, this will have to do.
This is exciting times where we invent stuff...
In a cave!
With nothing but scrap metal.
Wait, I got rid of my thingies.
I need these.
This is like the whole shebang, you know?
This is what we need.
Okay, so let me see here.
What else is new?
We're gonna make one of everything.
Let's make a gantry shaft, dude.
Gantry...
Did I really put this back?
Where did my alloys go?
Huh?
Wait, I'm actually so confused.
Oh my god, we need andesites.
Did I...
Where did I put my alloys?
Maybe I used them all.
Let's go get some andesite real quick.
This will not stand.
I knew I should have picked up more.
Wait, do we have some...
We have something there.
Good.
I'm so good.
Oh, shit.
Hey, you asshole.
Come here.
I'm gonna grab this, and then later...
We're gonna use it.
I want a lot of this now.
I like that they actually make blocks that normally aren't useful for anything.
Useful for something.
Like andesite.
I would be...
Or I would not be surprised if diorite also has a use.
I can't even say the frickin' word without thinking of the meme that you guys have...
Like, you guys have made a mountain out of molehills regarding that, you know?
And now every time I say it, I'm like, ugh.
Here we go again.
The block that shall not be named.
I've got one stack so far.
Let's get two stacks.
And then we're gonna make a...
Jeff!
Samuel Jackson.
Those that haven't seen that.
It's a good one.
We should get into that.
28.
Industrialization starts now.
Well, in approximately 37 seconds.
When we get home...
That's good enough.
And now we have a ladder.
Lucky pig.
Love rotating that.
That feels good.
It is weird, though, seeing something just sort of...
Rotate.
Isn't it?
Like, in Minecraft, this is...
Such a weird sight to look at.
It's like when you're in a car, you know?
And you wanna get some air.
Yo, what if you can actually do that?
When I make a car, I'm gonna have a window that I can, you know, pull down with that.
Alright.
Now we have a bunch of andeside.
You know what that means.
I'm gonna alloy the shit out of this.
53 andeside alloys.
Now we're cooking.
So I...
Uh...
Yeah.
Let's make a couple more things.
I'm actually just gonna make this.
To see what happens.
Okay.
That is expected.
Thanks.
Gantry shaft, coming up.
Ponder on it.
Gantry shafts form the...
Well...
No, I missed it.
Uh...
Go back.
No.
Why is the text not...
Gantry shafts form the basis of a gantry setup.
Attached carriages will...
Something.
Gantry setups can move!
With the help of superglued, larger structures can be moved.
What?
Really?
You can move that?
We'll move along with them.
Whoa.
What the fuck?
Superglu.
Huh.
Alright.
That seems insane to me.
This goes against everything that I know about Minecraft.
You know?
Oh my god.
That's actually such a...
Cool UI?
Can I turn it?
No, that wouldn't make sense, I guess.
Oh, and then it's like...
Like a barbershop pole, you know?
And then you put the gear on and it's gonna...
Yeah, I get it.
That is actually sick.
Okay.
Alright.
What else you got?
Let's make a radial chassis!
Radial chassis connect to identical chassis blocks in a row.
When one is moved by a contraption, the others are dragged with it.
The side faces of a radial chassis can be made sticky.
Oh!
With slime!
Slime ball!
The little...
Shh, shh.
You find off the slime dudes.
Sneak and right-click with an empty hand to remove the slime.
Remember a block is next to a sticky face.
It will attach all reachable blocks within a radius?
Oh!
This feels wrong!
What?
Wait, wait, wait.
What was that?
Say that again.
Within a radius on that layer.
Okay.
So these ones are ignored.
Using a wrench, a precise radius can be specified for this chassis.
Oh.
Oh my god.
Dude, this is like some advanced shit.
Blocks not reachable by any sticky face will not attach.
Ah, okay.
So it needs to be...
Yes, I get it.
Interesting.
So I guess windmill, right?
That's what that is.
Wait, whoa.
We just jumped ahead in the tech tree here.
What the fuck?
Look at all this.
Mechanical press.
That's the one I...
That's the one I know about.
You can make sheets with that.
Assemble a windmill of maximum strength.
I want to do that.
Dude, let's make a windmill!
I think...
I think that's a good start.
You know?
To start understanding this.
But I'm not going to use wind.
I'm going to rotate it myself with the hand crank.
That's the difference.
So it's a hand mill.
I'm kidding.
I'm not going to do that.
Am I?
Maybe I will.
What have I not tried here?
You know what?
Let's make a chain.
Okay.
Didn't do anything.
Let's do this.
That's just going to unlock redstone stuff.
But it's good to have.
Will the block of redstone be useful finally?
Oh!
I saw something new!
Something redstone-y.
Put it in here.
Powered toggle latch!
Hold up now.
Powered toggle latch.
What would that even mean?
What is a latch?
Powered latch.
Cockwheel!
Oh, that's an easy...
Okay, hold on.
I can make that.
Shaft me!
Oh, you make eight at a time.
That is actually a lot.
Let's make like...
64.
Wheel.
Let's make a normal cockwheel.
Ah, we need wood for that.
I have it.
Oh, Stuart!
You're not going to believe it!
There's cars and airplanes and shit!
And you're invisible.
You don't even have anything I want.
You know what?
I do have something you want.
I will take one flower that represents you and your life force.
And I will treasure this flower for all eternity.
Hey, I'm talking to you, Stuart.
Give me that one.
There we go!
What a deal!
For him.
We got some new recipes unlocked.
Um, let me...
I'm going to plant that on this roof.
Oh, what the...
That's a skeleton on a spider over there.
Oh, God.
You know what?
Actually, I don't want to be out here.
He has an enchanted bow.
Hey, dude!
How's it going?
Up!
Saved by the bush!
Oh!
Oh, shit.
For some reason, I expected you to just...
Oh, sorry!
I think I hit the...
The llama.
Stuart, okay.
You know what?
That's fine.
You can stay in here.
That's cool.
I was going to plant this thing, actually, on the roof.
I'm going to do that now.
Except I don't have any dirt, which is kind of surprising.
This should do.
Stuart!
If that flower ever...
Wilts!
It means that you're dead to me.
And you're also literally dead.
Because if it does, I will come and find you and murder you.
So you better keep that flower alive, you hear me?
You gotta water it regularly.
You gotta feed it.
That's the rule.
Ah, this is the new stuff.
Dude, I love this...
Freaking...
Interface here.
This is so...
Like...
Like, technically, this is so well done.
And it's a mod.
You know?
Kind of blows my mind.
Wow.
Just from a technical perspective, this is like...
Above and beyond.
For a mod...
For a game, you know?
Why did that one just remain open?
You saw that?
Was that because Stuart was standing on it?
I'm not sure.
Um...
Alright.
I wanna go and crank some shit.
Oh my god.
Can we not show this fucking...
Lock?
Every time I go to bed?
Like, what's happening?
There you are!
Finally chose to show yourself, huh?
Uh-huh.
Wait.
The thing is, I don't know what's new.
Maybe I can, you know, sell things to...
People nowadays.
With the mod.
But I guess I can do that also.
Without the mod.
But you know what I mean.
Maybe just, you know, drag things on them and things happen.
Um...
I wanna make a windmill.
Uh, let me see here.
We need to make this.
Looks like that, doesn't it?
We gotta make this.
We gotta get white wool.
Right now.
Mission, white wool has been engaged.
Let's get it.
Sheep, where are you?
Actually, uh, wait.
Oh man, I wish I had a, um...
Like a rope.
So I can bring the sheep home and, uh...
Make them multiply.
Also, I have to remember not to get lost here.
Oh man, I...
Even if I find sheep, I don't wanna kill them.
Because I wanna use them.
I also forgot what sheeps eat.
Maybe...
Uh...
It's probably seeds?
Something like that.
There they are.
The whole...
Oh, there's like...
Oh my god!
Okay, I can easily kill some of these.
Boink!
Meh.
Yeah, yeah, I was about to say...
Does the sheep say meh?
It does.
I was thinking of, uh...
You know, the animal that walks on mountains.
I got eight white wool now.
Let's get up there and start flying.
Shall we?
Oh, there's my house.
Dude, if I can somehow...
Because...
Now that I know there's rotation, right?
I wanna make...
A freaking lighthouse.
A lighthouse!
That's it!
I wanna make a lighthouse.
You wanna...
When it rotates up top?
And have like...
A little flashlight, maybe?
That's a project.
Uh...
You wanna get out?
Or what?
You're not trapped, you know?
You can leave.
If you want to.
Uh...
Let me see here.
What was I doing?
Oh, yeah.
We're not gonna...
Should we make this?
Can I make an awning?
Ooh, hold on.
I gotta make...
Stuff like that, right?
Ooh, wait.
Water wheel.
Hold up!
I want this.
That looks amazing.
Let's see.
Oh, that's awesome!
Water wheels draw force by...
Yeah, I guess...
Movement of water makes sense.
Covering additional sides will not improve its kinetic...
Okay.
Man.
The text is too fast.
And why when I pause, it doesn't stay, you know?
Use wood planks on the wheel to...
Wait.
Comfy reading.
Does that do anything?
Water wheels draw force from adjacent water currents.
Okay, okay.
That's it.
It just didn't seem like it did anything at first.
Got it.
And then...
Covering additional sides will not improve its kinetic output further.
Okay.
Use wood planks on the wheel to change its appearance.
Not die?
Interesting.
Right click.
Okay.
This thing again.
I think it's showing how fast it's rotating.
That's what that gauge is.
I need to...
Wait.
This is like...
Have I not just discovered an infinite energy machine?
Like perpetual motion?
Because Minecraft physics...
I just put freaking water and...
Hello?
Wait a sec.
I have a bucket.
I need to try this right now.
Stuart!
Watch this!
You ain't never seen some shit like this.
We're gonna have it over here.
Right there.
Right.
That wouldn't make sense.
Hold on.
Let me just see this again.
Ah!
They put a little...
Okay, I see.
Put a little thing at the end there.
Wait.
Let me try something.
Can I channel a little bit?
I need to channel things.
Dirt.
Watch this!
Actually, uh...
You ready?
That's fucking sick!
Yo, it looks smooth as hell.
Look at that animation, though.
Oh...
Okay!
Yo, that's amazing!
Okay, uh...
Shaft?
Ha-ha!
All right.
What am I gonna connect to that, though?
So what do I do with this?
Hold on.
Let me think back to early history of mankind.
Why would you do this?
Why would you harness the power of rotation?
To generate electricity!
We need magnets!
No, wait.
That was before then.
Okay, what would you use it for?
You would use it to drive a blower on a forge to make things hot.
All right?
You would use it to create wheat.
Or, no.
Flour.
Right?
Because you want to have a thing that...
A press!
You power a press with that.
We're gonna make cake.
The modern way.
Wait, can I make that?
Oh!
Windmill sale!
That's what I needed!
Cocks are turning.
Wait, I unlocked a bunch of stuff just now.
Oh!
Dude!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I need to see this.
Large cogwheel!
I wonder if gear reduction is actually, like, a real thing here.
Like, how far it's simulated.
Like, I had to write some code to make the gear reduction work in that waiting screen today.
Hold on.
Let me actually not do this.
No, I actually kind of want the water to do this, but I want to make a little basin here.
Just so it's not going anywhere.
Like, everywhere, you know?
Like, this is perpetual motion right here.
Ha ha!
Sick!
Didn't I make another wheel?
Wait.
I like the sound of it.
Adding a bit of ambient sounds there.
I'm going to crank so hard.
Wheel.
Let's make...
Wait.
Water wheel.
Small...
Wait.
Cockwheel?
Large.
Is there a medium?
This is so cheap to make.
Let's make, let's make, uh, three.
And some, some more of this as well.
I just want to see this in action here.
Oh.
Look at that.
I wonder if I can make this spin even faster.
Hold on a minute.
If I start from higher up...
Nah, it's the same.
Okay.
Well.
Wait.
Uh.
Can I somehow...
Let me see.
If I put this here...
Oops.
Can I not put a shaft on this?
Oh!
I can.
Okay.
No.
Make it, like, the other way.
Maybe need to be, like...
I'm trying to see if I can get wind to interact with this as well to speed it up.
But I guess that wouldn't make sense with the water.
That would fight the wind.
Eh, it doesn't make sense what I'm trying to do, actually.
Ha ha ha.
All right.
Let me, uh, try this now.
Oh!
That's actually sick!
You gotta click on the sides of it.
That looks like...
Yeah.
This is spinning faster now.
Hey!
Wait!
Hold on a minute.
I just want to go smaller and smaller and smaller and smaller until I have infinite speed.
Obviously, it's not going to be very strong in that case, but still, it could be fun.
Okay, so I guess it's about angle, so maybe if I do it from up here?
I mean, I don't want to do this, but I just want to see how it interacts with it, you know?
Let me see this achievement here.
What does a windmill look like?
It's like a...
I can't explain it.
I'll make it.
We gotta make it.
I need more wind sails...
things.
You can also just make a frame.
Oh, just take the cloth off?
Sixteen...
windmill sails.
Oh, wait, I guess I would...
Oh, okay, I understand.
I need to be sort of...
Oh, I need to sleep real fast.
Stuart, are you keeping track of your flower up there?
I hope you're watering it.
Go to bed.
I really should do this in order, right?
Assemble a windmill and use it to generate torque.
But why would you like a empty frame?
What's the point of that?
Get launched more than 30 blocks by a weighted ejector.
Apply andesite alloy to stripped wood, creating a basic casing for your machines.
Let's do that.
I know how to strip wood.
If I have any wood.
I don't have any wood.
Should I consume this lone tree out here?
Do it.
Nobody's gonna see it.
Just looking at this breaks my brain.
The fact that this can even sort of work this smoothly in this game blows my mind.
Just seeing anything slightly roundish breaks my brain.
All right.
What did I want to make with this?
Oh yeah, the weird thingy.
What was it called?
Alloy.
Oh, right.
I had to...
The wood.
Wait, why can't I...
Does it need to be this way?
Oh!
I can't have a shield on.
This is the rule.
My inventory is...
Ass!
Oh wait, that...
Dude, what am I doing?
Put the shield in!
There we go.
I...
You know what?
How is it not possible to do this with a shield?
Maybe if you hold, like, a key by...
Wait, maybe if I sneak into it.
There's gotta be, like, a way to do it with a shield on.
I imagine.
Maybe not.
Maybe that's just a limitation of Minecraft.
So, what did it say?
Apply andesite alloy.
Oh!
Hey!
The andesite age!
Nice!
So, this is obviously made of, uh, this.
Wait, can I make that?
Here we go.
Andesite casing.
Brass or andesite casing can be used for decorate...
To decorate shafts.
Man, this is looking so cool.
Oh, so it's going through them.
That's kinda nice.
En-casing belts?
Uh, comfy.
Brass or andesite casing can be used to decorate...
Dude, I wanna make a belt so bad.
What can I use it for, though?
Why?
Did I just ask that question?
Me?
Who was using...
Frickin' flow?
Trademark.
To try and get items around?
This is gonna be so nice.
Shaft.
What is this thing?
It looks a lot like, um, the casing we have.
But a little different.
I thought it said asbestos.
I mean, that would be the modern age.
Okay.
Dude, I would love to make some asbestos.
Windmill sail.
Oh yeah, let's ponder this.
Oh!
Right!
Okay.
That makes so much sense.
I feel dumb for not realizing this.
They will attach to blocks and each other without the need of superglue or chassis blocks.
Ah.
Okay.
So you can't attach them to the pipe itself.
You need to put them on the blocks.
Oh, cool.
All right.
Color them.
Oh.
Right click with shears to turn them back into frames.
Okay.
Why would you do that, though?
What is the point of that?
I guess you reduce weight?
I don't know if that's...
Like, how deep is this simulat...
Simulation here?
Pondering about physics behavior.
Sales for windmill bearings.
Okay.
All right.
Whatever you say.
Depot.
Analog lever.
Do we have a digital lever?
Clutch?
That's a thing a car has.
And...
Okay.
Directional gear shift?
Dude.
I'm getting overwhelmed a little bit.
Chain drive.
That's probably for the belt.
Wait.
Symmetric sail?
Oh.
I see.
That's genius.
So that's a way to...
Ah.
You can decide direction with this.
Which is...
You know.
Not quite how that works.
But...
I like it!
What else would you do, right?
I was about to say...
Is there wind simulators?
Or like...
Is it a windy day?
Or whatever?
Okay.
So...
Let's see here.
I don't need this down here.
Do I?
I mean...
I can just attach a block to a...
Um...
Maybe I do need that, actually.
Get the fuck out of my house.
Stuart.
You're not welcome anymore.
You're not.
Alright.
Let's keep making new stuff.
Cart assembler!
Make it!
Hold that thought!
I'm gonna ponder on that.
Oh!
Hold on.
This is...
Powered cart assemblers.
Mount attached structures to passing minecarts?
Without a redstone signal, it disassembles passing...
Hold on a minute.
This is blowing my brain.
With the help of super glue, larger structures can be moved.
This is Tetris!
Using a wrench on the minecart will let you carry the contraption elsewhere.
I need to make a wrench?
Movement anchors...
Oh my god.
Steering wheel!
Wait.
Oh, can I make a boat?
That's a boat wheel!
Hold on.
Ponder on it.
Steering...
Oh, comfy.
Steering wheels provide precise rotational output.
Hold right-click to grab the wheel.
Alright.
Is there a keybind for this one?
And move the mouse to rotate.
Sneaking while turning the wheel snaps to 45 degree intervals.
Okay.
Maximum turning angle can be configured using the value panel?
Mind that bearings have to be specifically told not to disassemble?
Dude, dude.
Hold on now.
Ooh!
Hold on, hold on.
This is my brain.
Let's take it easy here, huh?
Let's make a wooden bracket, damn it!
Oh, I already made one of those, I think.
Put it in there.
Maybe it's time to eat a little bit.
Yep.
Okay.
I'm slowly, slowly building up some knowledge here.
I think we should just start making this windmill thingy.
But!
We need some kind of...
Let me see what that looked like again.
This thing.
Looks a lot like that, but not really.
You know what I mean?
Let me see if we can even see it.
Oh!
No, no.
It's gray.
And a side door!
This is a special door, I'm calling it.
When you go through this door, something happens.
What?
Excuse me.
Did you say drill?
That's not going to do what I think it is, is it?
Hold on.
I need to make a drill.
Dude, I'm imagining walking around with a...
You know, have you seen Zoolander when he walks through that, you know, through that tunnel, and he's like buff, and he's sweaty?
That's me with a drill in my hand.
Ready to fuck shit up, you know?
That's what I imagine when I see this.
So we need andesite casing, but hold on a minute.
This is not going to scale up!
Because, I mean, me walking out there and, you know, using my axe and some wood seems kind of inefficient.
So maybe there's a way to do that automatically.
Hmm.
But, for now, we're going to do it not automatically.
Oh, it wasn't that bad, actually.
Sick!
Yeah?
Change?
Uh, no.
Okay, let's check it out.
Kinetic stress impact is moderate.
Okay, I can't wait to see this.
No way!
When given rotational force, a mechanical drill will break blocks directly in front of it?
Huh.
Okay, but...
Its mining speed depends on the rotational input.
Wait!
We put it on a minecart!
No.
We put it on a belt?
No, wait.
I- I- I wanna make a tunnel!
Okay.
Um...
Contraption actors.
Components which expose special behavior when attached to a moving contraption.
Yeah.
Like a minecart.
Right?
That seems right.
Let's make a depot.
Oh, uh...
Depot.
Depots can serve as stationary belt elements.
Right-click to manually place or remove items from it.
Just like mechanical belts, it can provide items to processing.
Hey!
The press!
Wait, what?
What was that?
Hold on.
Wait, uh...
Okay, this is the press.
It makes it into a sheet.
Now this...
I- It's making it wet?
Oh, Factorio!
Targets for a mechanical arm.
Wait, this seems kind of deep.
Like, deeper than I thought.
I knew there was, like, a mod for making, you know, Factorio-style stuff.
But, wait, was that actually create all along?
Maybe that was create.
Um...
Okay.
So, apparently, you can also right-click on things.
Deploying.
I don't know what I'm looking at.
Wait, I'm confused.
So, bookmarked recipes first.
Oh, right.
Hot air envelope.
Wait, are you saying that if I put a cogwheel in here, it becomes a large cogwheel?
Oh, with some extra wood, I guess.
Oh!
Oh, that actually makes sense.
Extending it.
Huh.
Oh.
Okay.
Um...
Alrighty.
Hopper over an ingredient and press A to bookmark it.
Oh, okay.
I actually knew that, but I forgot.
There we go.
Uh, right.
What should I make next?
I kind of want to try this drill thingy.
Should we try something simple?
Check this out.
No?
I guess I would have to make a, um...
Like that.
Oh, my God.
I will never be good at doing this.
It's just like redstone all over again, you know?
Not knowing which angle to put things at.
Check it out.
You ready?
Oh, ho, ho!
Okay, that's dope.
That's really cool.
That is actually amazing.
You can go the other way.
And you can connect this, I guess, to the water wheel if you were so inclined.
Wait a second.
I wonder if I can...
I'm trying to think of a way to continuously dig down.
Like this.
I guess you would have to extend the rod continuously, or...
Um...
Wait, does gravity affect this?
Wait a sec.
Uh, where are you?
Did I not just...
Oh, there it is.
No, it does not.
Okay.
Because I was thinking I could put it upside down and just let it fall down and continuously drill, you know?
Assuming I can put some kind of battery on it and keep it rotating.
My inventory is a disgrace!
Terrible.
Put all this new stuff in there.
Man, I can tell this is gonna be...
tough for me to figure out all this.
This is...
There's a lot to unpack here.
Oops.
There's a lot to unpack.
But it's good that we...
I think...
Wait, what's that?
Chain conveyor?
This is what I...
Don't get distracted.
Just make...
The damn windmill, son.
But the problem is, I need a thing for that.
Or do I?
Maybe I don't need it.
Let me try something simple.
Something stupidly simple.
I'm gonna take a wheel.
I'm gonna take some sails, which I have.
Let's bring a block.
We got that, too.
Boom!
We got a wheel.
Now I'm gonna put a block.
Right?
Wait.
Aha!
There we go.
Spin!
Spin for me!
Oops.
Oh, shh.
Okay.
I want to make an automated turret and put it up on this roof so it can shoot zombies.
Lasers.
They've got lasers in their shoes.
Dude, I was drinking just when, uh, Stuart was drinking, too.
Okay, I think the problem is that this rod is literally stuck in the ground.
But now it's not.
You're free to move.
SpaceX can go fuck itself.
Okay, it doesn't work like that.
We gotta put something down here that will allow this to rotate, obviously.
And I think it's that thing in the ponder.
But I don't know how to make it yet.
So, let's just...
You know what?
Let's just make a bunch of shit that we can make and see if we unlock something.
Okay.
We need a throwaway, uh, box as well.
Wait, no.
Chest.
This is the throwaway chest.
Oh, things we never want.
Goes in there.
Okay, what else can I make?
Dude, I can't wait to try this.
We've made...
This, uh, gear shift seems like car thing, right?
Millstone.
That seems cool.
Let's make a millstone.
And the side casing.
I think we have one of those.
Yes.
Mill.
And a cogwheel.
Let's do it.
Mill.
Wait, what's wrong?
Oh, I don't have...
Cobblestone don't work?
And the side casing...
I guess it don't work.
Try this.
There we go.
Yeah!
Okay.
Millstone.
Oh, wait.
Calcite?
Becomes bone...
Wait, 75% chance?
Huh?
Alright.
Andesite...
Becomes cobblestone?
Cobblestone gra...
That makes sense, I guess.
Whoa.
Dripstone block...
Becomes a clay ball.
And bone becomes...
A couple different things.
Sugar.
That makes sense.
Black dye and gray dye.
Wait, you can make string out of wool?
That makes so much sense, actually.
Gravel into flint!
That is crazy.
Dude, we gotta make that.
Immediately.
And all we need is to have it rotate.
This seems super duper easy.
Watch this!
Give me this.
Let me get rid of that.
Okay.
Maybe it needs to be connected via a thingy.
Let me see this.
Aha!
They process items by grilling them.
They can be powered from the side using cogwheels.
Aha!
Nice.
I figured that out.
Aha!
Wheat!
Throw or insert...
What did I say?
This is what they did back in the day.
They made bread out of this crap, you know?
After some time, the result can be obtained via right click.
Ooh.
Does it have to be on this thing?
What is that, a worm?
Oh.
Oh!
That's fucking awesome!
The outputs can also be extracted by automation.
Okay.
We're gonna make a bread factory!
On one side, wheat comes in, and sugar.
On the other side, a cake comes out.
It's gonna be...
I'm gonna be sitting right here with my mouth open, and it's gonna go in.
Like this.
Cakes.
In my mouth.
That is wonderful.
See, to me that looks like...
Wait, I'm an idiot.
Wait, what is that?
Why doesn't that spin, though?
Shouldn't that spin?
Maybe this needs to be connected to something before it can spin.
Yeah.
Maybe if you just put it in the air like that, it's not actually gonna be moving, you know?
Also, I was like, this looks...
This is not a cockwheel, but in my brain, it's like, it's spinning, it looks like a cockwheel, it's a cockwheel.
But it's not.
How do I actually...
Oh, I guess I just use the top.
Obviously.
That's how you do it.
And then on the side, we're gonna put this here.
Too close?
Too far?
Need a smaller one, maybe?
Need wheels.
Wheel me!
Wheel.
That's what I need.
Oh, wait.
Do I...
Do I have to sort of...
Ah!
I get it now.
You can't put it down.
You have to sort of...
Hold it...
Ah, okay.
I wasn't understanding their game, you know?
But now I get it.
Also, it looks like you can't put it straight...
Um...
Like...
Across...
Along cardinal directions.
Oh, that's cool.
Alright.
Now we're cooking.
We're almost cooking.
We're almost there.
I thought I had to put the wheels on...
But maybe you can also do that.
There's different ways.
If I remove this...
Aha!
It's too close.
Hmm.
But what if I put a bigger wheel?
Can I somehow...
No?
Can I not sort of...
Do I have to sit while doing it?
I just want to put it next to it.
Maybe you cannot put a big wheel next to a big wheel.
It has to be like...
This...
And then you do...
Ah!
Okay.
That's weird, though.
Very cool.
I could just put it on top here...
But I'm not...
I don't want to do that.
I want to try the thing from the side.
I need to see this again.
Okay.
So here they have a wheel...
At a right angle.
But it doesn't look like that's working.
Like it's not spinning.
Ah!
There we go.
I was about to say.
Got it.
So you want to have a little wheel.
I could also remove this now.
But can I not just put it here...
And have it work?
Oh, I can!
Okay!
Good!
Very nice.
Let's put some stuff in there.
Let's...
Let's shred a steak.
Never mind.
Why can't I shred my sails?
I just want to shred, yo.
Like, I want to put my meat in there and make minced meat.
Is that not a thing?
If I can make some bolognese?
No.
That's cool, though.
Let me see that animation again.
I can't see it because it's not in my thingy.
Wheat!
And something else.
Oh, I guess I can see it here.
All right!
That's how I'm doing this from now on.
I don't have to have it in my inventory.
It's all going to be over here.
That's how that works.
So I'm going to do this, and then I can always refer.
Wonderful.
So what was the...
Let me see the examples they gave here.
So there's wheat.
I can also click on it like this, I guess.
Yeah, here we go.
Antecides.
Dude, this seems super nice.
Calcite to bonemeal.
Maybe there's finally a way that I can automatically plant seeds.
There's got to be a way to do it.
Not with this machine, probably, but something else down the line.
I want to be able to automatically plant my damn seeds.
Sugar cane.
Wait, coal.
Yeah, okay, okay.
I guess as I discover more, they're going to appear.
Alrighty!
Now, why is this bastard not spinning?
Maybe it's not a windy day?
Let me see this thing again.
I mean, it's obviously on some object down there.
I got to explore...
or find that.
They use three sails here.
Let me just see if it's actually something to do with that.
Maybe you need a certain amount of sails.
Let's not rule it out yet.
Also, we don't need this.
Now we do...
Oh, that's actually so nice that there's a preview here.
Yeah, it's not working.
We got to connect it to something.
I want to try something.
Let's say I have my hand cranked.
Would I just be able to do this?
Like, it's nonsensical, but...
I'm a little hand cranked gremlin.
I'm sitting down here and I'm just cranking.
Oh!
Wait!
That's not working, is it?
Why is that?
You got to crank the wheel.
But I guess you cannot connect the wheel to this directly.
That's the trick here.
That's the whole thing.
Oh my god, I'm getting so overwhelmed.
It's crazy.
I'm losing my mind.
Piston extension pole.
Let's make one of those.
Let's ponder on that!
Without attached poles, a mechanical piston cannot move.
The length of pole added at its...
Back determines the extension range!
Dude.
Are you ready?
Show me again!
Redstone.
Why do you need redstone?
Oh!
Oh, it stops it!
And then, when he activates...
There he goes.
Okay, so redstone is like arresting them.
Similar to the hoppers.
It's saying, Ah, no more!
Even though there's rotation, we say, Nope.
Not today.
Cool.
But now, see, I'm thinking...
Let's make a piston.
I have an idea.
I shall do it underground!
This is gonna be so damn cool.
If it works the way I think it does here.
Shaft.
Oh, wait.
Wait, this is a weird-looking piston.
That's not just a piston.
That is something else.
I see now.
I see.
We got the wrong piston.
I was like, Where does the pole go?
It doesn't fit.
But it makes sense.
Piston...
Looking thing.
Not that one.
Wait, a physics assembler?
Wait, okay, so...
Vertical gearbox.
Does this do what I think it does?
Gear...
No, uh, wheel.
Large.
Wait, what's the difference?
Why are there two of them?
Oh, you can make it in different ways.
Either you make...
Oh, right.
You use a normal cock wheel and add wood to it, make it bigger.
Just like a map you add wood to it, make it bigger.
I learned that.
Thank you.
But I guess a water wheel could also do the trick.
Then I don't need to crank it manually!
Hold up.
Ideas are forming.
Synapses are firing.
Brain is wringling.
But for that to work, I need this specialized piston apparatus.
And I don't have it.
But I keep getting distracted.
The millstone...
Is doing its thing over there.
It's just spinning and spinning.
I think I may need to just go out there and find more stuff.
This was already like...
As soon as I got the sink going, everything just exploded here in my crafting table, right?
The depot.
I really want to make that press.
I just don't know how.
Let me see this again.
Maybe by the shape we can sort of...
Think about it.
So this looks like an anticide casing.
With like a little keyhole looking thing.
And a hole in one side.
Wait a sec.
That looks a lot like what I have here.
We should try and make this stuff...
Yeah, just make one of each.
This is the rule.
So we need cocks.
And we need wood.
Wood.
I don't have enough wood.
Damn.
Let's go get some.
Man.
Stuart and I are synchronized on that front.
I didn't bring my shield.
That's fine though.
Maybe there's a machine to automatically chop down wood.
Oh my god.
Imagine.
I guess you could maybe do it with the drill.
If it's going to destroy any block.
My guess is that...
You probably need more force.
Depending on the block you're trying to destroy, you know?
So if it's something soft, you don't need a lot of force.
But if it's obsidian, then you need a lot.
That's a horrible tree.
What is that tree?
Look at that.
That's not a tree that's real.
It's a fake tree.
That's like someone who tried to paint or place a tree manually.
Okay.
39 oak logs should do the trick.
Now we have so many...
planks.
Look at that over there.
That's my little industrial base.
The windmill doesn't work yet, but it looks nice.
We should...
Dude, we can have a windmill...
on top of our house.
It's just now dawning on me...
the possibilities here.
Because if we have this on top of our house...
we can...
transport the rotational energy through...
into my house and do things with it down here.
Oh, sick.
We're gonna generate electricity.
This is gonna be amazing.
Anyway, let's make some wheels.
What was the reason why I couldn't do that?
Shafts.
Shaft.
Let's just make a shit ton.
48.
Now we wheel it up.
Okay.
And then we needed something else as well, which was the casing.
So now, of course, I...
Eww, destroyed all my wood.
Like a dumbass.
Dude, I love the sound.
Of these rotating.
What a pleasant sound.
Good job, sound engineers.
Good job.
Man.
It is Minecraft.
I mean, this is just pure Minecraft right now.
You're not gonna get around going out there and collecting wood all the time.
It's just the law of the game, you know?
No matter what you do or what mod you play, it's just...
you gotta get the wood.
It's a universal thing.
A little bit more.
And then we have to...
Wait, what am I...
Wouldn't it make more sense to strip them first before we...
But it is hard to do that on the way up, right?
I could do this.
Actually, it's totally...
Oh!
What is that?
Copper casing.
Oh, deploying!
That's like, um...
It's like applying.
Same word, I guess.
Manual item application.
Oh, no shit.
Oh, so it's...
It's a right click.
It also looks like a hand, actually.
If you look at it.
Which makes total sense.
Right?
Okay.
Also, there's something new here.
Depot.
What's new?
Andesite alloy.
Oh!
There it is!
There it is.
This is what I need to make.
And then we can automatically get the casings.
So I just need to supply some wood.
That's dope.
I like.
Except we haven't made this machine yet.
Okay.
Give me this.
We're gonna do this every time now.
I mean, you gotta do some manual labor here.
Nice.
I should do it.
Ah, no, I gotta do this again.
This is really not efficient.
It's twice the work.
But, you know what?
Actually, we can also keep some of them as it is.
Because I do want to finish the house a little bit more.
Also.
Or at least just the pillars on the sides.
Gotta get those up.
Is that...
It's actually not that bad of a house.
It looks okay.
But it could be better.
Stuart is taking care of his flower.
That's his life force right there.
Okay.
What do we do now?
What did I want to do just now?
We had the gears.
We needed the andesite thingy.
Ah!
Oh my god!
I can do two things at a time here.
I just realized my mistake.
We need to make more andesite alloys as well.
I should have...
I should have just right-clicked and then immediately put the alloy on there, you know?
That's the way to do it.
We have sink ingots...
Uh...
Alloy.
Wait, what?
Oh, okay.
Running out of andesite.
Again.
Shit!
Guess we're going mining.
Put some of this stuff in here.
There's a bunch down here.
It's actually kind of nice that I'm right next to it.
This water is annoying.
I'm also level 17, so pretty soon we're going to be able to enchant pickaxe and actually start mining a little faster.
Just combine those.
I'm also definitely jumping the gun a little bit here, trying to make all kinds of contraptions.
When in reality, what I really should be doing is to set up a basic food supply.
You know, create a little farm, harvest some wheat, and then we can even process that with the mill.
We should keep it really simple at first.
And that's actually what I'm going to do.
I just want to get some basic ingredients here, like...
some andeside, and...
so I can make some alloys.
It's easy to get distracted, though, you know, when there's so much cool shit.
I'm getting some stone at the same time here, but maybe that's okay.
Some of these recipes take stone, as well.
Let me see.
Almost two stacks.
I could also make a pyramid at some point.
But I have a feeling maybe there's better ways to enhance your mining.
A.K.A.
the drill.
Make a little staircase.
Okay!
Very good.
Imagine if I can make a teleporter.
You know, I click on it, like a handheld one, and I teleport back to base.
That would be broken as hell.
That's too much.
Now we need these.
Now we're going to make a lot.
Boom.
48.
Could even make more.
I'm going to make more.
So we turn these into that.
And then we alloy it.
What's that?
59.
Not bad.
Now with all of these,
I was going to do what exactly?
Wheel.
Shafts we have.
Cockwheels.
I really want to experiment with that right now, but I think we should just stick to the windmill.
Yeah.
Let's make a hole.
We got some seeds.
I'm going to make a little bit of a farm here.
Keep that in there.
Actually, carry this around so we can use them up.
Also, you've got to have a shield on you.
Is that it?
Nothing else I need for that, right?
Maybe some...
Oh, forgot I had this.
Yeah, I should really be doing this.
But I have it working.
I think I can probably make a blast furnace on steroids.
Because if we can somehow force wind in there and make it ultra, ultra hot, you know?
That's probably a mechanic.
I can see it.
And, obviously, there's also these I've got to pay attention to.
Create some sheets and a mechanical press.
Windmill of maximum strength.
What about this stuff?
Oh, okay.
So this item here is...
simulated stuff.
Obtain a physics assembler, the heart of every simulated contraption.
I'm going to wait with this.
It's probably going to overwhelm me.
If I do that.
I'm not even going to look at this yet.
We stick to this for now.
Keep it simple.
This is the next big thing I want to make.
After the farm.
Okay, so a hoe.
Give me that.
Can you stop making noise?
Thank you.
Yo, actually, hold on.
We do an EDP here.
I want your pearl.
That's probably a crazy recipe with that.
Or not.
But maybe there is.
I can't wait to shoot the Enderman with a gun.
La pistola.
Diddle in.
That also gives experience.
That means I should be cooking everything here.
Maybe I should set up a simple hopper system.
You know?
Chest.
Needs wood.
Simple hopper system.
Nothing too fancy.
The cool thing is, though, that now, with the knowledge that I have, that I can just be like, yeah, let's make a little hopper system.
It's kind of funny.
Wait, what, what, what, what, what, what, what?
Oh, chest.
Scatterbrained.
Hopper me now.
Thank you.
There we go.
And then we, actually, we needed, uh, two hoppers.
Now we fill this up with everything we want to cook.
Yeah, I guess we could cook some food as well.
Anything else we need to cook here?
This one?
There we go.
May not have enough coal for that.
Okay.
Farm time.
We also need some water.
We have that over here.
I don't need a lot of it.
I need to make a basic food supply of grain to make bread.
That's like the base, baseline here.
It can be down here, I guess.
I do want to put it next to this, kind of...
Ah, fuck it.
Dut, dut, dut.
Dut.
Getting achievements as well.
Lovely.
Actually, let me actually look at that.
Yep.
Okay.
This is a good start.
Now I can probably, uh, kickstart that a little bit with some bone meal.
I'm pretty sure I have a couple bones.
I do.
I do have bones.
Meal.
Yeah.
More recipes.
Now we're cooking.
Whoa!
New recipe!
Let me see.
Millstone.
Wait, actually?
We could actually make wheat.
Oh, there's a small chance to get even more wheat.
Wheat flour, I mean.
Okay, we definitely got to do that.
Wait, can we, can we then...
Wait, what am I going to be able to do with wheat flour?
Because normally when you make bread in Minecraft, you just take, you know, the wheat, and you turn it into bread directly.
Skipping the whole baking process.
Maybe you can make nice bread.
Much more nutritional bread or something.
Anything else?
This one.
Bone meal turns into white dye.
This one is crazy.
Let's actually add some gravel to it.
We can do it manually, right?
Get some flint.
Now, the big question is, maybe there's a way to get more feathers.
Because getting feathers in Minecraft is one of the most painful processes that has ever existed in gaming.
There's no shortcuts.
You gotta get out there and torture chickens just to get some...
feathers.
Right.
That was that.
What did I want to do just now?
Oh, yeah.
Gravel.
I only have one gravel?
Thought I had more.
Alright, well.
Let's see.
Huh?
Wait, do I need to...
Oh!
It's mashing it!
Oh, wait.
Oh, you weren't done?
Sorry.
Oh, did I miss?
Embrace the grind.
Use a millstone to pulverize materials.
What happened to it?
Did it fall out?
Oh, shit.
Nope.
No, no, no.
Stop that.
Where did it go?
Wait, what's supposed to come out of that?
Flint.
Did I get a flint?
Oh, maybe it's not 100% chance?
Let me see here.
No, it is 100% chance.
Let me see what it said.
They grind them.
And there was something at the end about extracting it.
Okay.
In it goes.
After some time, the result can be obtained by a right click.
Maybe with an empty hand?
Oh, okay.
I get it now.
Alright.
Sick.
Dude, we're gonna make so many flints.
That's amazing.
We actually have seven already.
Not bad.
Dude, I like this.
This felt...
This feels good.
This is really nice.
And then we can do this again.
I still have some bone meal, don't I?
Did I actually use all of it?
No, wait.
I had like 20 or more.
Maybe I did actually.
Did I have just enough to use it everywhere?
That's unbelievable.
Hey, we got some weed out of it.
Our first bread.
Aw.
Nice.
Let's try and put this weed into the smasher.
smash it.
Oh, yeah.
Grind that up.
Grind it.
Takes a while, doesn't it?
Weed flour!
Oh!
We can make dough!
That's 100% dough.
Right, though?
Ah!
With water!
What about salt, though?
Bit of salt, maybe.
Bucket.
Yo, I need to have like an infinite water supply here.
We gotta take care of that now.
There's no way I'm running to and fro this place every time.
Actually, we put it over there in the in the farm area and then we take from there.
This is the way.
So we make it infinite here and then we take it to over there.
There it is.
And now we can just go like boop!
Wait.
Wait a second.
Can we do that with three only?
I have always used four.
Like, I always did like a square.
Why did I never do this?
I'm thinking back to the machine days when I was making the machine.
I would always make a square.
Why would I...
Why did I do that?
That's like hella inefficient.
Weird.
Is that a cute little farm I have?
I really...
I can't believe I haven't farmed more in Minecraft.
It's just so nice.
Nice.
Okay, now we have water.
Let's make dough.
Oh.
Ah, what?
I can make slime out of dough?
Wait, what are you saying?
That is fake!
That's not real slime!
That's just green dough!
What do you mean?
That's like someone trying to pass off slime as something else.
Or pass off dough with dye as something else.
But I like it.
That's kind of funny.
But it is nice because normally slime balls are kind of a pain to obtain.
Yeah.
Are you cooking?
So this should...
I can just take this now and it should automatically just...
Eww...
...afterwards.
That's amazing.
I got a lot of iron now.
Good to have a supply.
What else can I do with this?
All right.
But maybe the dough can make like more bread.
Maybe that's the whole key here.
Maybe it was a special machine.
Maybe I need a different type of furnace.
There's probably like a different type of furnace.
Oh.
Wait a second.
Maybe I'm losing my mind.
Has dough always been a part of Minecraft?
Because I've made a cake before.
So I must have done the dough somehow?
But in a different way?
Maybe I...
I don't know what I did.
I've made a cake before.
I know this.
Unless...
This is just one of two.
There's also a different recipe.
There's a different recipe.
I see now.
Wow!
That...
Okay, this takes way less milk somehow?
Still needs a hell of a lot of resources which is annoying.
Okay, I get it.
I get it.
Well, still a pain to make cake.
The cool thing is I can take this energy from that rotation and bring it to my house with gears and shafts.
And then I can have something in here that does the grinding for me, right?
In fact, how about we just do that now?
Let's go to bed first.
Keep it simple, right?
We're going to focus on making a nice little millstone inside the house.
Probably going to be annoying while we sleep, but...
They're burning.
Ah, but wait a sec.
Yeah, I can spring the water.
But I was going to say, I kind of want to make a windmill so I can use that energy to drive the millstone.
It's a little more pleasant.
That's going to look so cool to have that on my house!
Wow!
I'm excited.
But I still need that specialized object.
That is so mysterious.
Nobody knows where it comes from or what it is.
The hell?
Oh, that's a tablecloth.
Now, the gearbox!
That's the thing I've been wanting to make.
So let's actually make it.
Yeah.
And to do it, we needed these doors and gears, which we have.
And what was the last thing?
The casing.
The painful thing.
Don't have any of those yet, but I can make them because I have this and that.
This is not pretty.
I will say though, this is kind of a nice floor!
Yo!
I like that!
We even have, like, a little border at the edge here!
Just like real life!
Oh my god, I can make a super nice house.
But first, we make the millstone machine.
Big fan of that.
Okay, now that we have this gear, let's make a gearbox.
Okay?
Vertical gearbox.
Nice.
Let me actually click on that.
I know what it's going to be.
Jumping between axes of rotation can get bulky quickly.
Yeah, that's why you want the gearbox!
It's going to do this but easier.
Yeah!
So I guess there's just tiny, um, cogs in there that you can't see.
Hey, what did that say?
Hold on.
More compact equivalent
shafts around corners rotate in mirrored directions.
Ah, okay.
I guess that makes sense if you think about the cogs.
This one goes that way, goes that way, goes that way, yeah.
Straight connections will be reversed.
Mm-hmm.
That way.
Moves this up.
Yeah, it makes sense.
Makes total sense.
It's making sense.
cool.
So I wonder now, if I can just use a gearbox underneath this fella.
Not that way, though.
Let me see.
Not that way, either.
Let's try that one more time.
Maybe if I do it like that.
Brother!
Ah, I need the vertical gearbox.
Of course.
So now, hypothetically, if I were to crank this son-of-a-gun from this side...
Hey!
I like it.
Now we just need to figure out how to, you know, abuse the wind.
Also, I'm going to take this back.
This machine will wait.
Not yet.
Dude, I'm having such a blast with these little contraption thingies.
I'm also going to try this thing now.
Dough!
Punch it!
Yeah!
Need that dough!
And it's done.
Good.
Don't think you can actually do that, but it would be funny if you could.
What if I can make a fridge?
So the idea is to have a shaft come down through there as soon as we figure out the windmill.
Which apparently is like one of the first things you can do in this game, so.
You know.
Oh!
The hammer is in the game!
Sick!
Alright.
I wasn't sure.
Very good.
Armadillo.
This needs to happen ASAP.
I need to get my
spyglass is the word for it.
Thank you, dear lord.
Is my wheat ready?
Not yet.
Okay, so let's see what else we can make with this casing.
This is where I was.
We can try and make it encased chain drive.
Encased chain drive.
chaos computes.
Let's ponder on that one, shall we?
Let's really rack our brain.
Oh, okay.
Chain drives relay rotation to each other in a row.
So there's like a little belt in there.
Or gears.
No, it's a belt because it's turning the same way.
All shafts connected like this will rotate in the same direction.
rotation.
Okay.
What was that?
Oh.
Any part of the row can be rotated by 90 degrees using the wrench.
Controlling rotational speed with chain gear shifts.
Okay, yeah, no, that's too much for me right now.
Take it easy.
Let's build some more stuff.
What about the analog lever?
Yeah, what's this?
analog levers make for a compact and precise source of redstone power.
Really?
How is it any different from just a normal lever?
Right click to increase its analog power output.
That's how it's different from a normal lever.
Anything else?
Oh, fine control.
Right click while sneaking to decrease.
Wait.
Let me try that.
Oh, oh, that is actually so nice.
Makes you think why the fuck was this not part of the game to begin with?
Oh, my God.
Oh, wow.
Oh, oh, oh.
Possibilities.
Let's put that in this one.
What else we got?
Block of andesite alloy?
Wait, gearshift?
I'm going to ponder on it.
Gearshift will relay rotation in a straight line.
Oh, okay.
Wait, is this the thing I need?
When powered by redstone, it reverses.
Oh.
Ooh.
Okay.
Dude, this seems insanely complicated.
Like, all these things together, you can make some wild stuff.
Very nice.
This thing looks like some kind of science fiction thingy.
I've made all of this.
This one I have not made.
I could make a clutch, but that's, like, car-related.
I think we just start exploring some.
And getting more materials.
I kind of want to try this, though.
Hand the side door.
Let's do it.
I'm very curious.
Oh, that's cool!
Okay, I'm a fan.
That is amazing.
How fan... I mean, I don't know if it's actually useful to sign, but it is cool looking.
It's like those supercars with those weird doors that open in the weirdest ways.
Just give me a normal door.
But, uh, that looks cool.
What else, though?
Have we exhausted the current repertoire?
I need to take one last look at the windmill stuff.
So, notice the block that it's on.
It's, like, very, um...
Whatchamacallit?
Gray.
Right?
So, maybe it's related to deepslate.
Or some kind of block from down there.
Down below.
You know?
Like basalt.
Or something like that.
But if it was, I would have seen it.
Let's make a block of iron, shall we?
I'm gonna make one of each.
Not just one.
Ah!
There we go!
Okay, let's keep making things.
Block of copper, for sure.
Oh my god.
My inventory is so full.
In.
Everything in.
Maybe you stay.
Okay.
Copper me.
Yeah, that's new stuff.
I saw it.
Oh, what was that at the end there?
Looked like a grenade.
Copper.
Back.
Tank.
A wearable tank for carrying pressurized air.
Provides pressurized air to equipment that requires it.
When placed, powered by kinetics.
Collects pressurized air at a rate.
Depending on the rotational speed.
What?
Okay, I gotta see what this is all about.
It adds four armor.
Okay.
Also, finally got this one.
Mechanical press!
Yeah!
Let's go!
Eureka pending!
That's a big one.
Oh my goodness.
Compacting?
Okay.
Gravel.
And flint.
Makes andesite!
Wait, lava?
Oh, I put lava in or...
Pressing.
Copper sheet.
Wait, I can make a dirt path.
Oh!
Haha!
That's funny.
Sugarcane to paper.
Gold ingot to golden sheet.
Ooh!
I can make diorite out of calcite and flint?
Normally, I would have, like, I would have looked at this and gone, bro.
There's no way I'm making andesite from flint.
But now we can get flint easily if we have gravel.
Right?
So that's nice.
Basin?
Oh, this is a basin.
Let me actually ponder on this stuff.
Oh, I can't ponder on this.
But I can ponder on this one.
The mechanical press can process items provided beneath it.
The input items can be dropped or placed on a depot under the press.
Dude, this belt looks so sick.
The press will hold and process them automatically.
This is factorial!
Up next, compacting items.
God, this looks insane.
Wait, what does it say?
Pressing items held in a basin will cause them to be compacted.
Yeah?
Okay.
I can probably compact snow and do something with that.
Wait, what?
Compacting includes any fill 2x2 or 3x3 crafting recipe plus a couple extra ones.
Okay, so wait.
If I put wood?
What does that become?
Uh.
Some of those recipes may require the heat of a blaze burner.
Oh.
Okay.
So I capture a blaze and I imprison him underneath the basin.
The filter slot can be used in case two recipes are conflicting.
This is kind of crazy.
Okay, I mean...
Still, I'm still limited by not being able to get power from wind.
This is my biggest issue right now.
Right?
I mean, I could just make a little water slide up there and have it, you know, spin like that.
But I want a windmill!
I want to mill the wind.
Let's just keep making blocks.
This is, uh...
Doing things for us.
What else can I make?
Block of gold!
Let's do that.
Oh, I don't have nearly enough.
All right, then.
Bone block, maybe, but I don't have this.
But I do want to try the...
Oops.
No!
Do I have to...
Ah!
Let's say I hand-cranked that bastard.
Oh, I guess I could do that, yeah!
Oh, the other way?
Crank for me!
Why is it not cranking?
Is it the other side?
Wait a sec.
Let me see this again.
How are they...
Oh!
They need a wheel on it.
But why can't I just rotate that?
With my hand?
Maybe I'm not strong enough!
I mean, a press is supposed to be pretty damn strong, right?
That's the whole point.
Yeah.
And again.
It would make sense if it was consistent.
Let me try something.
What if I take a shaft?
Shaft!
Keep this.
Ah.
Did I just...
Okay.
See?
No.
It's definitely rotating.
Maybe I did something wrong with that.
If I crank it now...
I guess maybe you need a wheel on it.
Or a gear.
Cog.
Yeah.
Put that there.
Put this here.
Oops.
Yep.
Actually, let's just make it simple.
Transport it over here just to test proof of concept.
Ah, but now it's...
Ah, of course!
Mistake.
Take a small wheel.
Here.
Let me do this.
Can I just connect it like this, maybe?
Oh, wait.
This doesn't even make sense what I'm trying to do here.
Ha ha ha!
I need to rotate that wheel.
Except maybe I cannot with a small one.
I think I need another big one.
Also, I'm gonna sleep.
Just so we can see better.
Oh, this is a lot to take in, man.
I'm trying to purposefully go slow.
To not be...
Or feel overwhelmed.
Hey!
At least a lot of my stuff survived!
Oh my god, dude.
I can't believe it!
Fucking assholes, man.
All right.
Oh, we lost so many levels!
Dude.
I was at like level 20 or something.
What a pain.
Also, water is gone.
I didn't mean to remove the water.
Whoops.
Let's grab from the infinite water source.
IFS.
Whoa!
Nice.
It's spinning!
Okay, and now?
Let's just equip this again.
Man, that sucked.
Where's my axe?
So now we're gonna do this.
Why are you not spinning?
Or like, uh...
It is spinning, look!
Is it...
Angled or wrong?
Say I were to put a block...
Here?
Oh, where's my shovel?
Okay.
Why is that not doing the...
Smash it!
Maybe it needs to be higher.
I'm losing my mind.
How is this not exactly like the drawing?
Hold on.
I'm really looking.
Yeah?
Oh, wait!
I get it!
Oh!
Okay, hold on.
I understand.
I get it now.
Here it comes!
Hand!
Ah!
Fuck!
Wait.
Did I get four copper ingots for one?
What the fuck?
Hold on.
Do it again.
Oh, wait.
I'm an idiot.
Right.
It just...
Okay.
The way I picked it...
It looked like there was a lot of ingots on here for some reason.
I don't know what I was thinking.
Obviously, we made this.
What if I...
Smash the sheet?
We'll smash, okay?
It's somehow sentient.
It knows that it shouldn't smash...
On the sheet.
Hmm.
Can you smash a pork chop?
Smash it!
No?
Okay.
Let me see here.
What can I smash?
Right.
Okay.
Well, let's try some iron and gold.
Those sheets can probably be used for something quite useful.
Iron we got.
Now we just need a couple gold bars.
Let me actually bring this too.
And while we're waiting...
Compacting.
Gravel and...
Okay.
Got it.
So we obviously got to apply more force here.
To make this...
Bonk faster.
Okay.
Let's have a look.
Oh, great smasher!
Smash my gold!
Oh!
Was that the wrench?
Oh my...
Oh my god!
Okay, dude.
We just unlocked a shit ton of stuff.
More.
Smash!
I think...
Wait, was that a saw?
Hold on a second.
Wait.
I just got mega excited.
Is that a telephone?
Minecart coupling!
That sounds awesome!
What is that?
Copper valve?
Hold on.
Valve?
Are you saying...
Fluid?
Are you saying the flow?
Steam whistle!
A whisk!
What?
We can make whipped cream, maybe.
Fluid pipe!
Oh, man.
Wait.
Brown toolbox?
Every inventor's dearest companion conveniently holds a large amount of eight different item types.
Oh, yeah.
Holy shit!
When picked up, retains inventory contents.
When placed in range, nearby players can hold the toolbox.
Keybind to access its contents remotely?
When right-clicked, opens it.
Okay, that sounds...
I don't even know what that sounds like, but that sounds awesome.
I need it.
Ropes!
Wait, that's pulleys?
There's no way they're simulated rope stuff.
Metal girder.
Propeller.
This looks like a mouth.
Steam vent.
Wrench.
I can make this.
Almost!
Hold on.
Wait, also!
Wait a second!
Why wouldn't I just keep...
Let's say...
Okay, hold on.
Check this out.
Is it not just gonna go bonk?
Bonk, bonk.
And then I come back later and I just grab a bunch?
Let me see.
Let's watch.
So I definitely made one.
Get out of here, pig.
We're sciencing.
Keep bonking!
So, okay.
Hold on a minute.
Give me this.
No!
Don't!
Wait, can I actually do that?
Bonk my pickaxe!
Make it stronger!
No?
Okay.
Would be cool, though, if you could do that.
I'm gonna try and see if I can use some gear reduction here.
Oops.
Ah, my inventory!
I don't need this.
Who needs meat?
Not me.
Eh, eh.
Can I?
Oh, wait!
Gearbox!
Oh!
Gearbox time!
I sense a usage.
But I guess there's no reduction in that case.
Ah, that should be.
Mathematically.
Wrong way.
Oh, wait.
Maybe I can't do this.
God, I...
My inventory sucks.
Yes!
Can't handle it.
And somehow I picked up the meat again.
Stop picking up the meat!
So this gearbox...
No, we need a vertical gearbox.
Damn it.
It's over here, isn't it?
Guys, I need, like, 30 seconds to calm down.
Oh, man.
This is...
Oh, my inventory.
I wanna die.
You know what?
I...
Everything in!
I don't give a shit anymore.
Clean it up!
Fucking nuked it from orbit.
Essentials.
Now.
Take a wheel.
Take...
The gold.
And this.
And...
This one.
Nope.
Grab the thing.
There you go.
I hate this hole I made here.
I regret making a hole.
Wait, we gotta try this thing, don't we?
Are you saying that I can crank that shit?
Oh, my God!
Dude, that is freaking cool!
So you're, like, in the middle of exploration, you take it off, you go, I'm gonna crank my bank.
There we go.
Let me see.
Wait, it's not even getting filled!
Hold on.
Collects pressurized air at a rate depending on the rotational speed.
Okay, maybe it was just too slow.
Let me keep cranking that shit here.
The other way, perhaps?
Wait.
No?
It looks like air particles are coming in.
Doesn't matter which direction I do it.
Reminds me of the particles from the enchanting table.
The way they came in.
Let's just keep cranking it.
Very inefficient.
You don't want to do this, I guess.
Ah!
We are filling it up!
Okay, that's awesome.
So, does that mean...
If I wear this...
Can I just breathe underwater?
We got...
Oh, I don't have any food.
I can't sprint.
Did I not just deposit everything into that?
There we go.
I was about to eat the copper bar.
I mean, I would love to do it.
That's always been one of my biggest complaints.
Like, why can't you do that?
Doesn't even make any sense.
Okay, let's just go over here and try and see if we can swim forever.
Also, we have these boots on!
I'm actually so excited to try this.
Okay, that's...
That's pretty cool.
Wait, can I...
Do I have to take these off?
I gotta get up.
So, I absolutely do not have breath.
I think I may need to connect this tank to some kind of breathing apparatus.
Preferably made out of kelp.
And then we can establish an aggressive beachhead.
And start hunting down you and your family.
You lose that battle.
Nine times out of ten.
Let me see if I can actually make something like that.
Okay, hold on, hold on.
We gotta try this.
I keep getting distracted.
But what's that?
A steam engine!
Wait a second.
Are you saying I can boil water and get motion?
Because that sounds awesome.
Would love that.
Plow?
Wait, wait.
As in plowing the field?
Can I make a...
What's it called?
A tractor?
There's no way.
My mind is blown right now.
Hold on.
One thing at a time, dammit.
So, calm down.
We found a lot of new stuff.
And we gotta go to bed.
Shit.
Okay, fine.
Get off my homestead.
Come here.
Good night.
Take you out.
Oh my god.
There's monsters everywhere.
Can I not create a Terminator to go around and just kill things?
Wait, what if I lead them into the rotation?
Will they take damage?
Can I grind these orphans?
What if I make a saw?
Can they die?
I will make a saw and try to make them run into that.
Shit!
Door technique.
Ah!
Fucking hell, let me sleep.
I'm gonna lead them around.
And come back.
Dude, we need to set up a perimeter of light.
It's like basic Minecraft shit and I'm failing at it.
I can't live.
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?
I may actually use this opportunity to set down some torches.
I know I have some.
Do I?
What?
There they are.
Nope.
Oh, God.
Ooh.
Man, oh man.
There we go.
Look at this.
Nice perimeter.
You shall not pass.
It's like putting salt down, you know?
Along your...
What's the word for this?
Threshold.
Just a little bit more.
Maybe this is overkill, but you know.
This area is under heavy construction.
And science is being conducted here.
We cannot have monsters walk in on us.
Disturbing us like this.
And boom.
That's actually perfect.
Much better.
What was I doing?
Put these back on.
Right.
I was testing this copper back tank.
So, it says, Provides pressurized air to equipment that requires it.
Okay.
So, I gotta find some equipment that requires pressurized air.
I'm assuming it's gonna be some kind of diving helmet.
I would love for that to be the case.
I don't think I have it unlocked, though.
We need these.
Let's go press some bars.
Do your thing.
Ah, but wait.
That's what I was doing.
I was trying to make this go faster.
And I was using a gearbox for that.
That is way too slow.
We gotta put this on that.
Let's try...
A couple more small cogs here.
By the way.
I need to see something.
Yeah.
Only diagonally.
Shifting from large to small cogs.
Yes.
I think the opposite way.
Invade speed will be hot.
Yeah.
Yes.
I just need to connect it properly.
So, I guess what I can do is perhaps add a little bit of shaft to this.
Also, I gotta go feed Jackie and take a break in a second here.
It's feeding time.
Yep.
You wanna...
You wanna eat some food?
It's gonna connect the shaft.
Daddy's gonna connect the shaft.
It's very important that Daddy does this.
There we go.
Now watch.
Wait.
I guess I need a big wheel here first.
So you would do this.
And then you would do...
Oh, wait.
That's not diagonal, is it?
This is not gonna be diagonal.
Oh, God.
Wait.
What am I even trying to do?
Why won't that go...
Oh.
Shit.
I see.
Hold on.
Need this one first.
Then we gotta do...
That one there?
And then...
I mean...
Okay.
You know what?
Fuck it.
We can also build this over here.
It doesn't really matter where we put it.
Let me put that on the other side.
Just to make it easy here.
I wish this would rotate me like this when I'm standing on it.
That would be kind of funny.
Maybe it would get old really fast.
There we go.
And...
Then on the other side.
There.
Give me that one.
Oh, Jackie.
I'll be right back, guys.
I'm gonna take a break, feed my cat.
And also feed myself a little bit.
I'll be back in like 10 minutes.
I'll see you again.